字幕校对+特效: 月亮花@MySiLU思路高清
试金石影业出品
这是地球，
[Man Narrating] This is the Earth at a time...
是恐龙称霸的时代,万物滋长、欣欣向荣
when the dinosaurs roamed a lush and fertile planet.
一块只有六英里宽的石头
A piece of rock just six miles wide...
却改变了这一切
changed all that.
它以一万枚核弹的威力撞击地球
It hit with the force of 10,000 nuclear weapons.
一兆吨的灰尘和沙石 散布在大气层
A trillion tons of dirt and rock hurtled into the atmosphere,
令人窒息的灰尘掩盖大地
creating a suffocating blanket of dust...
一千年内阳光都无法穿透
the sun was powerless to penetrate for a thousand years.
曾经发生过的…
It happened before.
…将会再次发生
It will happen again.
主演 : 布鲁斯·威利斯
这是迟早的问题
It's just a question of when.
【 世 界 末 日 / 绝 世 天 劫 】
(六千五百万年后)
宇航员，请重复
请你重覆
我收到了，休斯顿
[Man] Houston, affirmative.
我要再试一次
Now try again.
就快好了
Almost got it. [Grunts]
阿特兰蒂斯号，我快好了 休斯顿，彼特的状况不错
Dennis, I'm almost there.  Houston, Pete's lookin' real strong.
很好，彼特 我们看到联轴器了
Okay, Pete, we got that coupling on the board here now.
等它对准以后 我们就通知你进行操作
We'll give you the goahead from down here when it's in alignment.
没有问题,给我十秒钟
Sounds good. Give me ten seconds.
他的心跳加速
His heart rate's racing. Hey, Pete.
彼特，我是楚门
It's Truman.  Hey.
你在上面还好吧，伙计？ 很好
How you doing up there, hoss?  Pretty good.
彼特，我看到你的生理迹象
Listen, Pete, we got an eye on your meds here. I'll give you a buffalo nickel...
要是你能冷静下来 我就送你奖品
if you'll calm down just a little bit.
你行不行？ 我都听你的
Can you do that for me?  Whatever you say.
很好，我们的时间充裕 你不要急
Okay, now, we got plenty of time, buddy, so don't you worry.
进行得很顺利
Looking good here.
行了
He'll be all right.
继续吧，阿特兰蒂斯号
Go ahead, Atlantis.  Roger that, Houston.
收到，开始把他拉进来
Suggest we start reeling Pete in.
那是什么玩意？
[Buzzing]  What the hell is that?
天啊
My Lord.
信号中断
We're down!
休斯顿！
Houston!
完全失去联络
We've lost all contact.
老史，再放一次
Stewart, play that tape back!
休斯顿！
[Screaming] Houston!
“五角大厦，太空指挥部”
我们受到攻击，受到攻击
Multiple bogies! Multiple bogies!
第59区有三…五个不明物体
Sector five, niner. I have three. Now five.
荧幕都满了
Unidentified tracks.  My screen's full.
它们飞向大西洋海岸
Multiple tracks headed toward the Atlantic seaboard!
我们可能遭到导弹突袭
This could be a surprise missile attack.
总统先生，航天飞机在外太空爆炸
Mr. President, the shuttle Atlantis just exploded in space.
我需要三组人!第一组，进行内部检查
Okay, I want three groups! One: internal malfunction.
从头到尾彻底检查 也许是机件故障
Get the log tape. Start working back. Maybe it's a glitch.
第二组 请北美空防和太空指挥部
Two: I want NORAD, Space Command and the 50th tactical,
比对每个轨道上的外太空物体
comparing all the space junk you tracked in every orbit.
我要你们比对以后再比对
I want you to check, recheck and then do it all over again.
最后一组，考虑突发状况 设想所有的可能性
Number three: wild cards. Anything and everything.
老罗，快打电话把太空总署的一万一千名人员动员起来
All right? Now, Big Ross, get on the telephone. Wake up 11,000 people.
让他去,快点
Walt, get 'em going.  Let's go!
卡尔…卡尔…
Karl. Karl! Karl.
卡尔
Karl! Your Stouffer's pot pie's...
你的烤肉馅饼十个钟头前就凉了
been on the table almost ten hours.
我要跟你离婚 -妲蒂，发生一件大事
I want a divorce.  Dottie, I'm on to something big here.
我不晓得是什么,看来外太空有东西爆炸
II don't know what this is, but it looks like something's burnin' up there.
快去拿我的电话簿 我的电话簿
Go get my phone book, will you? Get my phone book.
帮我查太空总署的号码
Get those names of those guys from NASA.
对不起，我脸上有写着 我是卡尔的奴隶吗？
Excuse me! Am I wearing a sign that says, "Karl's Slave"?
快给我去拿电话簿！
Go get my goddamn phone book!
快去！快去！
Get the book! Get the book! Get the book!
太空指挥部确认了,没有任何国家发射导弹
Space Command is reporting negative. That is zero global launches.
这些可能是坠落地面的航天飞机残骸
It might just be a piece of the shuttle breaking up as it comes in.
也可能是圣诞老人
It might be Santa Claus.
没有获得准确的答案之前，将军
Until we get definitive, reliable confirmation, General,
我们就得进入备战状态
we go to DEFCON Three.
* I'm gettin' ready for the big time *
* Someday you're gonna say I'm big time too *
小狗狗，
Hey, little man! Little Richard!
我跟你，咱们要发了
Me and you, man! We're going to the top, baby!
发大财了,我不想一辈子都骑脚踏车
Big time! I ain't gonna be ridin' this bike for the rest of my life.
你知道吗？我要骑摩托车，
You know what I'm sayin'? I'm gettin' a motorcycle, baby.
这样才拉风
We're gonna travel in style.
* I'm gettin' ready for the big time *
* Someday I'm gonna be in big time news *
你有没有长眼睛？赶着去投胎吗？
Watch where you're goin'. I bet you, none of you all stop for brothers.
慢点跑
Slow down, Little Richard.
我们骑了整个早上 你想要大便么？
You've been ridin' all morning. You gotta take a dump?
我们中断节目
We interrupt our regularly scheduled programme...
为您报导最新消息…
to bring you this special report.  Shh, shh, shh.
航天飞机于东部时间凌晨 3点47分在外太空爆炸
The shuttle Atlantis exploded in space at 3:47 a.m., Eastern Standard Time.
还给我
Hey! Get, get.
那是我的哥斯拉
That's my Godzilla. Come on, now.  Yo, fool!
胖子，你干嘛欺负我的小狗？
Don't be kickin' Little Richard. What the hell your problem?
它在咬我的哥斯拉 你这小黑想怎么样？
That dog's eatin' my Godzilla. What's a little runt like you gonna do about it?
狗狗，去咬他.如果我不是基督徒
Get him, Richard. Sic him. If I wasn't no Christian,
早就把你这身肥肉拿去榨油了
I'd be throwin' your fat pineappleeatin' ass through the window.
你为什么还不走？知道吗？这里是纽约
Why we not going?  You know why? 'Cause this is New York City.
什么怪事都有,搞不好有恐怖份子放炸弹
Anything could happen. Let's see. Could've been a terrorist bomb.
或是有人被枪杀,今天发薪水
Could've been a dead body. Somebody shot, stabbed, and it's Friday, payday.
搞不好有人被炒鱿鱼跳楼
Dude, somebody probably didn't get their paycheck. Yes?
我想要去逛街
I want to go shopping.
我也想,不过碰到塞车 哪儿也去不了
Me, too, but we ain't goin' nowhere 'cause this is a traffic jam.
小狗狗
Little Richard!  Right over there!
我来了，小狗狗
[Screaming]  Little Richard!
撑着点，我来了
Hang on, Little Richard. I'm comin'!
别怕
[Whimpering]  Don't you worry about it.
我会救你的
I'm gonna get you outta there!
你没事吧？撑着点
You okay, buddy? Don't worry about it. Hang in there.
快打911
Somebody dial 911!
屏幕都满了,到处都有
My screen's full. They're all over the place.
从芬兰到北美海岸 都有物体冲进大气层
Bogies are breachin' the atmosphere from Finland down the North American seaboard.
你们看看
Look at that!
开战了！
Oh, we at war!  [Screaming Continues]
萨达姆打过来了！
Saddam Hussein is bombing us!
我们得专心算出它的路线
Let's stay focused. We need to map the trajectory now.
那得花一星期
That could take a week.
快去做，我要知道 这惨况将结束还是刚开始
Just find it, okay? I wanna know if the worst is over or if it's on its way.
金将军来电
We've got General Kimsey on the line.
从芬兰到南卡罗莱纳州 都受到攻击
We've got hits from Finland to South Carolina.
这些不是导弹 到底是什么？
We know they're not missiles. Now what the hell is it?
这是一场流星雨 它们也把航天飞机击落
It's a meteor shower. That's what took out the shuttle.
总统马上要知道答案
I've got the president on Air Force One demanding answers.
结束了吗？
[General] Is it over?
将军，太空总署有一万一千人在查
General, we've got 11,000 people at NASA trying to figure that out right now.
一有答案就告诉你
When we know, you'll know.
卡尔，请仔细说
Okay, Karl, listen. I want you to take your time. Yes, sir.
你绝对是第一个发现它的
You're definitely the first.
第一个座标是1239…
Okay, first coordinate. Onetwothreenine. 1239, right?
联邦调查局找到他的位置了,他看到外太空发生爆炸
F.B.I. locked his location.  Saw an explosion in space.
好了
Okay.  [Whispering]
-听着卡尔，这是最高机密 -我当过海军，
Listen, Karl, this is top secret.  Sir, I'm retired Navy.
懂得保密条例,但是有一件事，
I know all about classified. But one more thing.
第一个发现它的人 有权利为它命名，对吧？
The person that finds her gets to name her, right?
没错
Yes, that's right.
我要用我老婆的名字命名，妲蒂
I wanna name her Dottie, after my wife.
她是个老巫婆 我逃不出她的手掌心
She's a vicious lifesuckin' bitch from which there's no escape.
你可真疼老婆 太空搜索组，我是指挥中心主任
That's sweet, Karl.  S.D.I., this is flight director!
马上启动哈伯太空望远镜
I wanna get that Hubble movin', and I want it now.
收到
Roger that.
启动哈伯望远镜
We're movin' the Hubble!
这玩意好大
[Man] It's enormous.
这是16时43分的图像
This is the anomaly at 1643.
这是16时58分的图像
Here is the anomaly at 1658,
这是17时的图像
and here is the anomaly at 1700.
别说什么狗屁图像了！
Enough with this anomaly horseshit!
-这到底是什么玩意儿？ -一颗陨石
What is this thing?  It's an asteroid, sir.
它有多大？
How big are we talking?
估计有九百七十六亿…
Sir, our best estimate is 97.6 billion
-跟德州面积差不多，总统先生 -是的
It's the size of Texas, Mr. President.  YYes, sir.
我们事先一点儿都不知道？
Dan, we didn't see this thing coming?
计算星体撞地球的预算只有一百万美元
Well, our object collision budget's a million dollars.
只能探测百分之三的太空
That allows us to track about three percent of the sky.
恕我直言，太空大得很
And begging your pardon, sir, it's a bigass sky.
早上掉下来的呢？
And the ones this morning?
它们微不足道
Those are nothing. They're the size of basketballs...
只有篮球或甲壳虫汽车那么大而已
and Volkswagens, things like that.
-这玩意会撞上地球吗？ -我们正在全力计算
Is this going to hit us?  We're efforting that as we speak, sir.
-损失会有多大？ -损失？
What kind of damage are we  Damage?
全面性的损失
Total, sir.
我们管这叫地球杀手，
It's what we call a global killer.
人类将会灭绝
The end of mankind.
不管它撞上哪里
Doesn't matter where it hits.
一切都将被毁灭，包括细菌
Nothing would survive. Not even bacteria.
我的天，我们该怎么办？
My God. What do we do?
在它撞上地球之前，我们只有18天！
We have 18 days before it hits Earth.
(南中国海)
早安
[Man] Have mercy.  Rise and shine!
停止钻油…停止钻油…
Stop the drilling! Stop the drilling! Stop the drilling!
球来啦！
Fore!
差一点打到我们
Hey!  Hey, that was close!
我每年都捐出五万元
I give you 50,000 a year in donations.
他们干嘛这么生气，奇克？
What do you think they're so mad about, Chick?
他们认为...
Well, I think they feel...
钻油很邪恶
that drilling for oil is an evil thing.
你们的船也得用柴油！
You know how much diesel that clunker boat pumps out an hour?
有件事挺有意思,昨晚二号油井钻到180英尺
I just found out something interesting. Number two chewed 180 feet last night.
这是谁干的？我让你猜猜看
Who do we have to thank for this?  I'll give you two guesses.
不过你很清楚
But you're only gonna need one.
该死…小杰
Goddamn it, A.J.!
小杰
A.J.!
小杰，你在吗？
A.J.! A.J., you in here?
好啊，你还在睡觉，起床！
Oh, that's just perfect. In bed. Get up!
你找我吗？对，我找你
Uh, hey, you wanted to see me?  Yeah, I was lookin' for ya.
我看得出你在生气
You're pissed. Okay, I can see that.
我没有生气,你见过我生气
No. You know what, A.J.? I'm not pissed. You've seen me pissed.
这次我不只是生气
This is way, way beyond pissed, though.
你明知道我昨晚把二号油井关闭了
You know I shut down number two last night, right?
-我早有预感 -让我告诉你
Yeah, man, I had a hunch on that.  Let me tell you something.
有一天等你长大了
Someday, many years from now, when you're all growed up,
拥有自己的钻油公司
and you got your own oil company
和八百万美元的资金
and $8 million of your own money on the contract,
你这个笨小子就能 为所欲为、胡搞瞎搞
you can do whatever comes into that  little A.J.idiotin' mind of yours you want.
不过只要油井上写着我的名字 你就不能违反我的规矩
But as long as it says "Harry Stamper Oil" on the rig, you will not disobey my rules.
-明白吗？-我明白了
You got that?  Yeah, I do got it.
我要听你说五个字
All right, now I need to hear five words from you.
我不会再犯
[Together] Never do that again.
我真蠢，我是个白痴 我真不应该，我真笨
I'm a fool. That was idiotic. II mean, that was stupid.
我知道油井是你的
I'm an idiot. I know what name's on the sign. I'm not
你是怎么了？
What's goin' on here?  What's goin' on?
我搞砸了，很紧张
Well, ll mean, you know, I screwed up. I'm a little edgy.
-你在我手下多久了？ -很美好的五年
How long you work for me?  Five wonderful years.
这五年来 你从没有这么快认错
In five years, you have never apologized to me this quickly.
一定有问题，我要查清楚
Something's going on here. I'm gonna find out what it is.  [Stammering]
我这次知错能改 我要拿你当榜样
Well, I'm turning over a new leaf. I'm trying to learn from the man.
我要向你看齐
What would Harry do?
我不知道该怎么说
I'm at a loss for words.
我能解释
Okay, I can explain this.
-你能解释吗？ -当然
You can explain that?  I can.
我很想听你解释.站着别动
I would really like an explanation. You just stay right here.
葛瑞丝？
Grace?
-嗨，哈瑞 -我一直要你叫我老爸
Hi, Harry.  I have asked you repeatedly to call me Dad.
抱歉，哈瑞
Sorry, Harry.
起来把衣服穿上
Get up and get your clothes on.
你别走开，我马上回来
You just stay right there. I'll be right back.
这是我的计划
Here's what we're gonna do.
我要星体撞地球的每一个应变策略
I want every strategy we've got on nearEarth object collision.
任何想法、计划
Okay? Any ideas, any programmes,
哪怕随手写在餐巾纸上的念头
anything you sketched on a pizza box or cocktail napkin.
三十年来 舆论总在问太空总署是否有必要存在
For 30 years, they questioned the need for NASA.
今天就要给他们答案
Today, we're gonna give 'em the answer.
你知道这事吗，色狼？
You know about this, Rockhound?
-你早就知道 -不，我一点都不知道
You knew?  No, I had no idea.
哈瑞呢？
Where's Harry?
哈瑞，我知道你很生气…
Harry, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa. I understand, okay?
谁都会生气
You're mad. WhoWho wouldn't be mad?
-他会向你开枪的 -他才不会
He's gonna shoot you.  Nah, no, he's not.
哈瑞，你疯了么？
Harry!  What's wrong with you?
向上帝忏悔吧，小杰
Make your peace with God, A.J.!
他拿着枪，正在向我开枪
This guy's got a gun, man. He's shooting at me.
-哈瑞，这可不是开玩笑 -听我说，咱们先谈谈嘛
Harry, this is not funny!  Harry, listen to me! We can talk this over!
-这件事很严重吗？ -很严重
Oh, is this a serious thing?  Yeah, pretty serious.
大熊，帮帮忙
Bear!  What's up?
他在向我开枪 帮我挡一挡
He's shootin' at me. You see Harry comin', crack him with that wrench.
小杰的老爸临死前 你答应要好好照雇他的
You told A.J.'s dad just before he died that you would take care of the boy.
向他开枪应该不算照雇他
Now I'm not sure that shootin' him is takin' care of him.
把枪放下
Why don't you put the gun down?
别插手，大熊，让开
You don't want none of this. Get out of my way.
我只想让他先跑远点
Just tryin' to give my man a head start, that's all.
钻到油之前，你不该杀死你最好的手下
Not to mention the fact that I don't think you wanna kill the best man on your crew...
我不会杀他的
before we strike oil.  Aw, Chick, I ain't gonna kill him.
我只会打断他的腿 缺条腿照样能干活
Just gonna take a foot off. A man can work with one foot.
法兰克缺一只手照样能干活
You remember old Frank Marx who worked with one hand all them years?
可是他干的并不好
Yeah, but he wasn't very good.
把枪放下，你疯了吗
Harry, put the gun down! You're acting insane!
亲爱的，穿好衣服站一边去
Now, honey, go get some clothes on and get out of the way.
-你不能控制我的生活 -好吧，去穿衣服，赶紧
-You can't control my life!  -Fine. Clothes. Now!
快住手，这可不是闹着玩的
All right, stop! All right!
快住手
It was funny for a minute. It's not funny any more.
你这算是违法行为
Fuck!  Harry, this is illegal, man.
我只是间歇性神经病发作，没有罪
I'm temporarily insane, Rock. It's all right.
我像疯子吗？
Do I look like I'm crazy to you?  Well
哈瑞，冷静点
Harry! Hey, just cool down.
快住手，住手
What are you doing? Harry, stop! Cut it out.
听我说，我很认真,我爱她
All right, now, listen. Man to man. I'm serious. I love her.
答错了
Way wrong answer!
哈瑞，别玩真的
Whoa, whoa, Harry. It's gettin' real.  Harry! Come on, Harry!
-你打到我了 -你打中他了
You shot me!  You shot him.
根本就没打中 只是擦伤而已
That bullet never got close. Just a ricochet.
有人受伤就不好玩了
You know, it's all funny till somebody gets shot in the leg!
伙计们，打起精神来 客户来啦
Hey, pucker up. We got clients incoming.
我们在…1974年…
Uh, bback inin in 1974,
就…想到…有…陨石…
wewe first got the idea
撞地球的…可能
thethe possibility thatthat a meteor or an asteroid
要找个不结巴的人来讲 博士，翻译给我听
I need somebody who's had a little less caffeine this morning. Doc, translate.
第一个方案是 用散焦激光
Yes, sir. Our first feasibility plan was to use a spreadfocus laser generator...
把陨石击碎
to heat the object to the point of fracture.
那就像对着火车头开玩具枪
That's like shooting a B.B. gun at a freight train, Doc.
我们有一个点子
Uh, some of us have got this idea.
派航天飞机在陨石上架风帆
We wanna land a craft, deploy solar sails.
利用这块大风帆 借着太阳风推动陨石
You'll have a big canopy. Solar winds will be caught by these Mylar sails.
伙计们，
Okay  Come on, guys!
实际一点好吗？ 只剩下十八天了
We gotta come up with something realistic here. We got 18 days.
那是431小时15分18秒
That's 431 hours, 15 minutes and 18 seconds.
-我们没有时间了 -干嘛？
Time's a luxury we don't have. What?
小杰是我的选择
Listen, Harry, A.J. is my choice.
不是你的
My choice and not yours.
这里只有他的年纪跟你差不多
He's the only one in your age bracket, Grace.
你是别无选择
It's not a choice. It's a lack of options.
你凭什么觉得
I don't know what in the world makes you think...
你还能控制我的生活？
that you have the right to tell me what to do any more, Harry.
就凭我是你老爸，这还不够吗？
I suppose being your father doesn't count, huh?
-那不是理由 -从几时开始的？
Not really.  Since when?
从我十岁时比你更成熟时开始
Since I reached the age of ten and became older than you, Harry.
或者从妈妈离开以后 两个“开始”随你选
Since Mom split. Why don't you take your pick?
你天生就很不成熟
Look, I understand that you  are handicapped by natural immaturity,
不过我原谅你
and I forgive you.
就算我当老爸不成熟 可我还是你的老板
I may be an immature father, but I'm still your employer.
我要你马上坐船离开
And as your boss, I want you on that crew boat tonight
礼拜一就回办公室
and back in the office by Monday.
-听懂了吗？ -好吧，我不干了！
You got that?  Okay. I quit.
你不能不干
Grace, you can't quit now!
我还需要你帮忙
I need you to keep on working.  [Speaking Chinese Dialect]
嗨，哈瑞
Hi, Harry!
你在笑什么？
What are you smilin' about?  [Speaking Chinese Dialect]
我和小杰约会有五个月了
I've been seein' A.J. for more than five months, Harry.
请跟我来
[Speaking Chinese Dialect]
你真没良心 我以前有管过你吗？
You little hypocrite. I ever held you back once from doing anything?
你是没有管过我
What about having a life, Harry?
我第一次来月经时
The first time I got my period,
是色狼带我到台北买卫生棉
Rockhound had to take me into Taipei for Tampax...
他还教我怎么用
and then he had to show me how to use 'em, Harry.
我只是跟她解释 没有亲自示范给她看啊
I ju No, ll told her how to use it. I didn't show her, Harry.
我的玩具不是洋娃娃 而是钛合金深度仪表
I was playing with titanium depth gauges when I should've been playing with dolls.
我从费弟的刺青上知道男女之间那事儿
I mean, I learned about the birds and the bees from Freddie Noonan's tattoos.
我被一群钻井工养大
Look, I was raised on roughnecks by you.
当我爱上这种人，你却大惊小怪
And now you get all shocked and shaken when I fall in love with one.
你说谁才没有良心？
So who's the hypocrite here, Harry, huh?
请看看那些油管多棒
Look at those nice pipes.
-听我说… -你听我说，我长大了
Listen to me, Grace.  No, you listen to me, Harry. I grew up.
陨石太接近地球 时间所剩不多
With the proximity of the asteroid and no prep time,
任何防范措施都没用
none of our primary plans can work.
为何不用150枚核弹把它炸成碎片？
Why don't we just send up 150 nuclear warheads and blast that rock apart?
烂点子
Terrible idea.
我在问你吗？
Was I talkin' to you?
这是研究部的昆西博士
This is Dr. Ronald Quincy from Research.
地球上最聪明的人,你最好听听他的意见
Pretty much the smartest man on the planet. You might wanna listen to him.
若是考虑陨石的
General, if you consider your target,
成分、大小…
her composition, her dimensions,
和绝对速度
her sheer velocity,
就算发射再多的核弹
you could fire every nuke you've got on her,
它还是照样会撞上地球
she'll just smile at you and keep on coming.
总统的科学雇问认为
You should know that the president's scientific advisors...
发射核弹能使它改变轨道
are suggesting that a nuclear blast could change this asteroid's trajectory.
我认识总统的科学雇问 我们在麻省理工是同学
I know the president's chief scientific advisor. We were at M.I.T. together.
碰到这种情况
And, in a situation like this, [Clears Throat]
最好别听一个天体物理只拿C-的学生
you really don't wanna take the advice from a man who got a Cminus in astrophysics.
总统的科学雇问错了,我才是对的
The president's advisors are wrong. I'm right.
爆破陨石的表面 一点用都没有
Hitting the rock from the outside won't do the job.
想想看，把鞭炮放在掌心
Imagine a firecracker in the palm of your hand.
然后点燃，会怎样？只会灼伤手掌
You set it off. What happens? Burn your hand, right?
若是用手掌握住鞭炮再点燃…
You close your fist around the same firecracker and set it off
你以后连开罐头都要老婆代劳了
poof your wife's gonna be opening your ketchup bottles the rest of your life.
你是说我们应该从陨石内部爆破？
Are you suggesting that we blow this thing up from the inside?
-没错 -怎么做？
That's exactly what I'm saying.  How?
钻洞
[Sighs] We drill.
找全世界最顶尖的钻洞专家
We bring in the world's best deepcore driller.
快上来，出问题了
Harry, get up here. We're takin' a hit.
叫小杰上来
Get A.J. up here!  Come on!
把油管抽出来，快点
Send another pipe down! Right now!
钻到天然气了
[Yelling Continues]  It's a gas pocket!
我就说吧，我是个天才
I told you! Am I lucky, or am I just a genius?
放油阀坏了我才关闭油井的！
I shut it down for a reason, you jackass! The relief valve's
关掉二号阀.葛瑞丝，快把客户带走
Shut off the number two valve! Grace, get the clients out of here now!
奇克，快把他们带走
Chick, get 'em outta here! Get 'em off the rig now!
快跑
Get the hell down!  This thing is gonna blow.
快点下来
[Yelling Continues]  Chick, get down now!
奇克，快下来
Get down!
我们打听过很多人 他们都推荐同一个人
[Dan] Three dozen research calls, and every time, the same man is recommended.
他熟悉地球上所有的地形
He's worked on every terrain this planet can offer.
最不可能钻洞的地质他都钻得进去
Whenever they said it couldn't be drilled, this guy drilled it.
-大伙没事吧？ -我们钻到石油了
Everybody all right?  We struck oil, baby!
刚才差点搞出人命 要这样你才甘心吗
Somebody could've got killed out here today. You want that on your conscience?
干得好，你太棒了
High thumb. You are man, Harry.
谢谢
Thumbs high.  [Helicopter Blades Whirring]
你被解雇了
You're fired.
哪位是哈瑞·史坦普？
Who's Harry Stamper?
我就是哈瑞·史坦普 有什么事？
Hey, I'm Harry Stamper. What's all this about?
我是孟将军 太平洋空军总司令
Mr. Stamper, I'm General Montgomery, commander of the Pacific air forces.
国防部长奉总统的命令
I've been sent here by the secretary of defense...
派我来这里找你
on direct orders from the president of the United States.
事关国家安全
[Chuckling]  It's a matter of urgent national security.
请你马上登上直升机 不要多问
I need you to get on that chopper right now, no questions asked.
疯子威利叫你来的吗？
Crazy Willie put you up to this?
我不认识疯子威利,我是认真的
I'm afraid I don't know Crazy Willie, sir. I'm dead serious about this.
哈瑞.怎么了？
Harry.  What?
我发誓我不知道她未成年
I swear to God, she never told me her age.
别紧张，他是来找我
It's all right. Relax. It's about me.
算我没说
Oh. Forget it!
好吧，我去,不过我有个条件
All right, General, I'll go with you on one condition.
我要带我女儿一起去
We're gonna have to take my daughter along.
我做了什么？
What did I do?
等等
Whoa, whoa, whoa. Where you guys takin' her?
先生，请呆在这儿
Sir, stay right here.  Wh
奇克，叫他们领了工资就放假
Chick, get him paid, get him off the rig!
(休斯顿，太空总署)
哈瑞·史坦普先生吗？
Mr. Stamper?  Yeah, I'm Harry Stamper.
你好
How you doin'? Miss Stamper.
史坦普小姐 我是丹楚门，太空总署署长
I'm Dan Truman, Executive Director here.
我要代表大家向你们…
Listen, on behalf of all of us, I'd really like to apologize
别向我们道歉
Apologize.
我们受够了
I don't know if we can take any more apologies, Mr. Truman.
这十八个小时来 一直有人在道歉
We've been apologized to for the last 18andahalf hours.
有什么话就请直说吧
So if you don't mind, how about if we just get on with it?
为什么把我们找来太空总署
You tell us why we're here at the NASA Space Center.
我们最好单独谈
We should probably talk alone.
我什么都跟我女儿葛瑞丝说
Mr. Truman, I don't keep any secrets from my daughter, Grace.
要么你直接说
So whether you tell her now or I tell her later,
要么一会我告诉她
she's gonna find out one way or the other.
所以你还是快说吧
So why don't we just get on with it?
这颗慧星撞上陨石带 它的碎片冲向地球
[Dan] So when the Rogue comet hit the asteroid belt, it sent shrapnel right for us.
未来十五天内 地球就像个练靶场
For the next 15 days, the Earth's in a shooting gallery.
就算陨石本身撞进大海 还是会波及陆地
Even if the asteroid itself hits the water, it's still hitting land.
它会使海水沸腾 然后直接撞进海底
It'll flash boil millions of gallons of seawater and slam into the ocean bedrock.
比如说它撞进太平洋
Now, if it's a Pacific Ocean impact which we think it will be
会造成三英里高的海啸
it'll create a tidal wave three miles high,
以一千英里的时速淹没加州 一直席卷到丹佛
travelling at 1,000 miles an hour covering California and washing up in Denver.
日本会直接消失，澳洲也会被淹没
Japan's gone. Australia's wiped out.
全球有一半人口将被高温烧死
Half the world's population will be incinerated by the heat blast.
另一半则被严寒冻死
The rest'll freeze to death from nuclear winter.
真不敢相信！
[Whispering] That's unbelievable.
这是千真万确的
Well, actually, this is as real as it gets.
它正撞向地球
Well, it's coming right now.
以两万两千英里的时速
Right for us at 22,000 miles an hour.
地球上谁也逃不掉
Not a soul on Earth can hide from it.
“15天零3小时”
我想你们还没正式公布吧
I take it you're not alerting everyone like this.
我们不打算把这消息公开
Nobody knows. That's the way it stays.
未来十天内只有九座望远镜看得到这陨石
For the next ten days, there are only nine telescopes in the world...
美国就有八座
that can spot the asteroid, and we control eight of 'em.
总统把这件事列为最高机密
The president's classified this information top secret.
要是把这消息公诸于世
If news like this got out,
全球的社会秩序就会崩溃
there'd be an overnight breakdown of basic social services worldwide.
造成暴动、宗教狂热,全面的混乱
Rioting, mass religious hysteria, total chaos, you can imagine.
就像圣经记载的世界末日
Basically the worst parts of the Bible.
全球有六十亿人
Six billion people on the planet.
你们为什么会找上我呢？
Why'd you guys call me?
我们要你训练上去的队员
We need you to prep the team we're sending up.
上去？
Up?
他们要到陨石表面 钻一个洞放置核弹
We'll send them to the asteroid, they'll land, drill a hole, they'll drop some nukes,
离开后引爆，不过器材有些问题
take off and detonate, if we can fix this equipment problem.
这是为火星计划打造的钻头
The drilling unit's a prototype we've been building for the Mars project.
你…你应该认得
You, uh You might recognize the rig.
我当然认得出,这是我设计的
Yeah, well, I guess I should recognize it. It's my design.
你们偷走我的专利？
Did you steal a key to the Patent Office?
基本上可以这样说
Yeah, basically.
让我搞清楚先
Let me get this straight. I got pulled off an oil rig,
我绕了半个地球跑来这里 却发现你们偷走我的专利
flown halfway around the world because you stole my drill design.
而且没有看懂图纸，做得烂透了
Couldn't read the plans right and did a pisspoor job of putting it together.
-在外太空没有专利权… -闭嘴，昆西
Patents don't apply to outer space.  [Dan] You shut up, Quincy.
钻头不再用于火星项目 现在只有它能拯救地球
It's not going to Mars any more. It's gonna try to save this planet.
你得帮我们搞定它
And we need to know what's wrong with it pretty quick.
你是说我们没做好钻头？
You said we did a bad job of putting it together?
不,我是说...
No, I said...
我是说你们做得烂透了！
you did a pisspoor job of putting it together.
首先，传送系统弄反了,让我猜猜
First of all, you got the flow system all reversed. Let me guess.
你们把叶轮拆开却搞不懂怎么用
You've been tearin' up rotors and you can't figure out why.
是的
Yeah, that's right.
那是因为凸轮装错了，天才
Well, that's because your cams are all wrong, Mr. Wizard.
谁负责操作这玩意？
Who's been operating this thing?
他们
Right there.  We've actually
我们让他们训练了八个月
We've had them training for eight months solid now.
整整八个月吗？
Eight whole months?
-差不多 -真服了
Well, pretty much, yeah.  Well, gee whiz.
这就上陨石的钻洞小组
Well, this is the team that has to do the job up there.
请你在这里训练他们
We need you to train them down here.
史坦普先生，怎么样？
Well, Mr. Stamper, what do you think?
钻洞是门科学也是门艺术
You know, drilling's a science. It's an art.
我是第三代钻井工 我一辈子都干这行
I'm a third generation driller, doin' it all my life.
还是没有完全搞懂
I still haven't got it all figured out.
我猜你是听说我最行 才会把我找来
I assume you sent for me because somebody told you I was the best.
那是因为我有最好的工人
Well, I'm only the best because I work with the best.
如果没有值得信任的工人 你就死定了
You don't trust the men you're working with, you're as good as dead.
你尽管派他们去吧
Now you wanna send these boys into space, fine.
他们是很好的宇航员
I'm sure they'll make good astronauts,
可是他们对钻洞一窍不通
but they don't know jack about drillin'.
-你有什么应变措施？ -应变措施？
-What's your contingency plan?  -Contingency plan?
备用计划 一定有备用计划吧
Your backup plan. You gotta have some kind of backup plan, right?
没有备用计划，
No, we don't have a backup plan.
只有这一个
This is it.  This is the best that you could
美国政府就只能想出这个办法吗？
that the government the U.S. government can come up with.
这可是太空总署 你们把宇航员送上月球
I mean, you're NASA for cryin' out loud. You put a man on the moon.
你们都是天才，聪明得不得了
You're geniuses. You're the guys that think this shit up.
一定有一大堆人在想办法
I'm sure you got a team of men sittin' around somewhere right now,
还有人在想备用计划
just thinkin' shit up and somebody backin' them up.
你是说没有备用计划？
You tell me you don't have a backup plan,
这八个人
that these eight Boy Scouts right here,
就是全世界的救星？
that is the world's hope, that's what you're tellin' me?
是的
Yeah.
老天，该死
Oh, Jesus. Damn it.
我们剩下的时间不多了 你能帮忙吗？
We're a little short on time here. Will you help us?
-他们只要钻洞？ -没错
All they gotta do is drill?  That's it.
不必太空行走，做什么高难度动作？
No spacewalkin', no crazy astronaut stuff.
只要钻洞
Just drill.
你打算要派多少人上去？
How many men were you plannin' on takin' up there?
两艘航天飞机，两组人员
We're sendin' up two shuttles, two teams.
我要用我的手下
If I do this, I'm gonna wanna take my own men.
没问题
You got it.
-你愿意帮忙吗？ -愿意
So you're saying you'll help us?  Yes, sir.
谢谢
Thanks.
我只是不相信别人
I just don't trust anybody else to do it, that's all.
不是，寇太太，
[Siren Wailing]  No, Mrs. Curlene.
我是哈瑞·史坦普, 你看到大熊就说哈瑞在找他
It's Harry Stamper. You see Bear, you tell him Harry's lookin' for him.
他们下了油井就乱跑
Those guys get off this rig, they scatter.
寇家强，绰号大熊
J. Otis Curlene Bear.
南达科塔州唯一的黑人骑士
Probably the only black man on a big hog in Kadoka, South Dakota.
来抓大熊呀
Come and get Papa Bear!
麦斯,外太空有没有体重限制？
Uh, Max.  You got a weight limit on the shuttle?
老妈
Max.  Hey, Mama.
你真乖
So sweet, Maxie.
你有没有买果酱甜甜圈？
Hey, would you give me one of them yellow jelly bear claws I like?
-又惹麻烦了吗？ -才没有
-Are you in trouble with the law again?  -No, Mama.
-麦斯 -我发誓，妈妈
Maxie.  I swear, Mama. I'm
我要色狼
You know I want Rockhound.
他很色，所以…绰号是色狼
We call him Hound because, well, he's horny.
到新奥尔良的每一家酒吧 应该能找到他
[Grace] You might wanna start with every bar in New Orleans.
这颗钻戒很大吧？
That is a big, shiny mount, isn't it?
-你结婚多久了？ -两个礼拜
How long you been married?  For two weeks.
-你看到吗？ -看到
See this diamond?  Yeah.
这不是钻石
It's not a diamond.
-想再喝一杯吗？ -好
Would you like another drink?  Yeah.
先生，联邦调查局
Sir, F.B.I.  So cute. No, thanks.
-事关国家安全 -那敢情好
We have a national security matter.  Good for you.
马上跟我走
Let's go. Now.
你到底几岁？
How old are you?
怪怪的奥斯卡 优秀的地质学家
Oscar Choice. Spacy but absolutely brilliant geologist.
他在德州有座农场
He owns a horse ranch outside of El Paso.
奇克查普先生
Mr. Chick Chapel, at the craps table.
他一定是在赌城的凯撒皇宫掷骰子
Caesar's Palace, Las Vegas, Nevada.
终于赢了
Yes! About time.
奇克·查普？别玩了
Charles Chapel, game's over.
要谁操作另一个钻头？ 班尼如何？他不错
Who's gonna run the other rig? How about Benny? He's good.
你应该知道小杰是不二人选
The only one who knows how to run it as well as I do is A.J.
你说他不值得信任
I thought you said you couldn't trust him.
你说他值得信任
I thought you said I could.
你也独当一面了，小杰
Yep, you are on your way, A.J.
自己当老板有很多好处
Well, being in business for yourself has its advantages.
不必打卡上班 没有人会开枪射我
Make my own hours, nobody shoots me in the leg.
你没带枪吧？
You don't got a gun on you now, do you?
那就好
Oh, good, 'cause I kinda wanted to get back to this whole thing...
咱们再谈谈 你为什么找我帮忙
about you askin' me for help.
难道无所不能的
Does that mean that there's a job...
万事通哈瑞·史坦普
that Mr. AllGoNoQuitBigNuts Harry Stamper...
也有搞不定的事？ 需要用到我的特长吗？
can't handle by himself and needs my expert advice?
算是吧
Somethin' like that, yeah.
这可不行，
Well, no, no, no, no, no, no.
你说算是 到底是不是呢？
I mean, is it something like that, or is it that?
我们真的合不来
You know, you and me got a real problem.
哈瑞，现在我只想听你
You know, Harry, there are only...
说出五个字
five words I wanna hear from you right now.
那就是
Those words are:
小杰，我佩服你
You know, A.J., I really look up to you.
你是我的偶像
You've been a hero of mine for a long time,
我好崇拜你，
and I'm very impressed with your work.
只是不好意思说
I'm emotionally closed off.
那好像不只五个字
That's like That's like 11 words or something.
那就说，小杰，对不起
You know what? How about just, "A.J., I'm sorry,
我爱你
and I love ya."  You know, A.J.,
小杰，在地球上，我永远都不想再跟你共事
there's not a job on the planet I want you to work with me on.
我是说真的
I mean that.
那你为什么要来？哈瑞，到底什么事？
So what are you doin' here? Harry, what's the job?
麦斯，好兄弟
Hey, Bear.What's up, baby? Yeah, baby. What's up? What's up?
怎么是太空总署？ 在天王星找到石油了吗？
What's up, Harry? Did NASA find oil on Uranus, man?
我们可以不去,我们大可坐在这里，
[Harry] None of you have to go. We can just sit here on Earth,
等这块大石头撞上来
wait for this big rock to crash into it...
摧毁地球上的一切
and kill everything and everybody we know.
美国政府要我们拯救世界
The United States government just asked us to save the world.
-谁打算拒绝？ -二十年来
Anybody wanna say no?  Twenty years.
我从来没拒绝过你 现在也不会
Haven't turned you down once. I'm not about to start now.
我参加
I'm there.
你不能一个人去
Guess I can't let you go up there alone.
我跟你去
I'm with you.
这是历史性壮举
I mean, this is this is historic.
我们是超级英雄
Guys, this is like deep blue hero stuff.
我当然参加
Of course I'm in.
虽然我没他那么兴奋 不过你也知道
While I don't share his enthusiasm, you know me.
送我上去吧
Beam me up, Scotty.
-你呢，麦斯？ -我不知道…
-You all right, Max?  -I..I don't I..I don't
你说去就去
Whatever you think.
-你呢？ -我去
-What about you?  -I'm in.
好吧
All right, then.
我们一起去
We go.
我不是斤斤计较，不过…
I don't mean to be the materialistic weasel of this group,
…我们有什么回报？
but you think we'll get hazard pay out of this?
如果你是想说服我 他们是合适人选，那还是省省吧
If you're trying to make me feel better about this scenario, give it up.
老实说，我很乐观
To tell you the truth, I'm kind of encouraged. This guy Chick here...
奇克当过六年的飞行员
was an Air Force commando for six years.
这些人干过抢劫、被逮捕过、还拒捕
We got robbery, assault, arrest, resisting arrest.
有一个人曾经替黑道收钱
We got a collection agent for the mob.
还有两个人坐过牢
Two of these guys have done serious time.
-他们是这行最顶尖的人才 -我也是
Look, they're the best at what they do.  So am I.
可我没你这么乐观
And I'm not so optimistic.
政府每年有两千五百亿的国防预算
We spend $250 billion a year on defence.
现在却得靠一群
And here we are. The fate of the planet is in the hands...
不靠谱的痞子来拯救地球？
of a bunch of retards I wouldn't trust with a potato gun.
他们怎么决定？
So what's the verdict?
他们答应了，不过有几个要求
They'll do it. They've made a few requests though.
什么要求？
Such as?  [Papers Rustling]
只有几个要求
Just a few things here.
很小的要求，例如说…
Nothing really big. Just Well, as an example
奥斯卡有几张罚单没有付
Uh, Oscar here's got some outstanding parking tickets.
7个州有56张罚单
Fiftysix tickets in seven states.
让我来说，奥斯卡
I'll tell him, Oscar. I got it.  Okay.
费弟有两个女友
Uh, Noonan's got two women friends...
想当美国公民，不能多问
that he'd like to see made American citizens, no questions asked.
麦斯想要大家…再使用匣式录音带
Max would like you to bring back eighttrack tapes.
-这恐怕不太可能 -还有什么？
Not sure if that's gonna work, but let's see what else.
奇克想到赌城的凯撒皇宫住一个礼拜
Chick wants a full week's Emperor's Package at Caesar's Palace.
你们能告诉是谁杀了肯尼迪么？
Hey, you guys wouldn't be able to tell us who actually killed Kennedy, would ya?
大熊想要住在…
Uh, Bear would like to stay at the...
…“白马”？
White Horse.
白宫，是白宫
White House. White House.
他想在白宫的林肯卧房
Yeah, he'd like to stay in the Lincoln Bedroom of the White House...
住一个暑假
for the summer.
差不多就这些
Stuff like that.
有些要求应该没有问题
Sure, I think we can take care of some of that.
哈瑞
Harry!
还有一件事
Yeah, one more thing.
他们以后都不想再缴税
None of them wanna pay taxes again.
永远都不缴
Ever.
这是干什么的？
Who's that for? Mr. Ed?
你敢用这扎我，我就扎你的心脏
You stick that in me, I'm gonna stab you in the heart with it.
你看过“黑色通缉令”吗？
You ever see Pulp Fiction?
他快死了，快点
We're losin' him, we're losin' him. Clear! Kaboom!
-费弟，你还好吧？ -你看我这样像是还好么？
-Freddie, you all right?  -Does this look okay to you?
还好，有点麻麻的
Does this look okay?  It's not all bad. It's kinda tingly.
查普先生，该你了
Mr. Chapel, you're next!
护士小姐，我只是来钻洞的
Oh, gee, lady, I just came here to drill.
哦～我也是
Oh, so did I.
三甘油化物指数太高
Your triglycerides are way high,
胆固醇量更是不得了
and your bad cholesterol is shockingly bad.
别吃太多肥肉
Gotta lay off those pork rinds, Bear!
肥你个头，给你看看吧
Pork rinds this! Yeah!
至少他们很有精神
Well, at least they're in good spirits.
太简单了,你想跟我比智商？
Piece of cake. Look, you wanna compare brain pans?
我十二岁就得奖学金 有什么了不起？
I won the Westinghouse prize when I was 12. Big deal.
十九岁出版论文 那又怎样？ 二十二岁成为麻省理工学院
Published at 19. So what? I got a double doctorate from M.I.T. at 22.
化学和地理双博士,我在普林斯顿大学教过两年半的书
Chemistry and geology. I taught at Princeton for twoandahalf years.
这是我待过最不舒服的房间
You know, I think this might be the most uncomfortable room I've ever been in in my life.
我为什么要当钻油工？因为干这行能领高薪、环游世界、
Why do I do this? Because the money's good, the scenery changes,
还能玩炸药
and they let me use explosives, okay?
尽管跟我玩心理游戏
Okay, you wanna be all psychological with me, that's fine.
我受不了大家都搞不懂
I'll tell you one thing that really drives me nuts...
邦乔维到底是歌手还是乐团
is people who think Jethro Tull is just a person in the band.
谁是邦乔维？
Who is Jethro Tull?
我最爱吃下水:心、肺、肝
My favourite dish is haggis. Heart, lungs, liver.
用羊肚包起来煮
You shove that all in a sheep's stomach, then you boil it.
骚得带劲儿
That'll put some hair on your ass.
我没有疯，我只是有点激动
I am not crazy. I'm just a little emotional right now, okay?
等你问完了能给我抱抱吗？
After this is over, could I, like, get a hug from you or somethin'?
那个女独眼龙好讨厌
Okay, Cyclops lady is startin' to bug me.
你能应付吗？
Can you handle it?
我当然能应付这件差事
I mean, I can handle what I'm, you know, gonna do.
我只是受不了这间房间
I can handle that, but I don't know if I can handle this room.
大波霸
Woman with large breasts.
中波霸
Woman with medium breasts.
这是哈瑞找我碴
Here's Harry givin' me a hard time.
这是他嫌我不够好
And this is Harry tellin' me it's not good enough.
这是他不让我娶他女儿
And this is Harry tellin' me I can't marry his daughter.
多谢了
Thanks a lot. I appreciate it.
尽管发泄吧
Just let it out.  [Crying]
我在高中的时候 大脑受过重伤
I suffered a major head injury when I was in high school.
这张很像你，也是波霸
This one looks like you... with breasts.
我当然能应付，我能应付
Yeah, I can handle it. Yeah, I can handle it.
全垒打 小熊队赢得世界冠军
A home run! The Cubs win the World Series! Ah
不合格，不合格 全部都不合格
Fail. Fail. Depressively fail.
有一个人有亚安酮反应
One toxicology analysis revealed Catamen.
那是效力很强的镇静剂
That is a very powerful sedative.
镇静剂很常见，大夫
Sedatives are used all the time, Doctor.
那药是给马用的
This one's used on horses.
他们有些人很强壮
Some of these guys are pretty big.
通常需要一年半时间
It would normally take 18 months to psychologically prepare,
评估是否适合上太空
prescreen viable subjects for space travel.
有些人有强烈攻击性…
We have seen evidence of a wide variety of territorial aggression.
他们的身体上得了太空吗？ 我只想知道这点
Can they physically survive the trip? That's all I need to know here, okay?
老实说，他们连测验都通不过
Personally, I don't know how they survived the tests.
“核准”
好一群太空狗熊
Talk about the wrong stuff.
早安，我是威廉·夏普上校
Good morning. I'm Colonel Willie Sharp.
我除了要驾驶X71 登陆陨石表面以外
In addition to flying one of the X71 teams to that rock,
还要训练你们在太空中 工作的心理和生理状态
my job is to train you to deal with the mental and physical rigors of working in space...
免得你们被吓坏了
so you don't freak out on the asteroid.
美国宇航员 必须接受多年的训练
United States astronauts train for years.
你们只有十二天
You have 12 days.
开始之前还有什么问题吗？
Do we have any intelligent questions before we get started?
X71是什么？
What's an X71?
这是第一次亮相
You're the first civilians to ever see her.
X71航天飞机
We call 'em the X71s.
这是和空军合作的绝密计划
It's a top secret joint venture with the Air Force.
这两艘航天飞机 明天将被送到佛罗里达
She and her sister ship in Vandenberg are leaving for launch prep in Florida.
我想先让你们看看
Thought you oughta take a look.
登陆陨石的航天飞机 分别是自由号和独立号
The two shuttles going up are the Freedom and Independence.
船身是钛合金打造
Her titanium alloy impenetrable skin covers the toughest, meanest,
是史上最坚固、最先进的航天飞机
most sophisticated space vehicle man has ever made.
戴维上校和宇航员塔克
Okay, Air Force Colonel Davis, NASA pilot Tucker...
将驾驶独立号航天飞机
will command the shuttle Independence.
夏普上校和宇航员华特 将驾驶自由号航天飞机
Air Force Colonel Sharp, NASA pilot Watts, shuttle Freedom.
武器专家古柏和哈斯负责放置核弹
Munitions specialist Gruber and Halsey will supervise the nuclear ordinance.
所以呢
Anyway, I just thought
我只想让你们…先见个面
thought you guys should meet.
各位，欢迎光临失重训练中心
Gentlemen, welcome to our weightless environmental training facility.
我们要在陨石上游泳吗？ 是不是这样？
So we're going swimming on this asteroid. Is that what this is for?
我们太空总署管这玩意叫“大穿山甲”
Here at downtown NASA, we call this monster "Armadillo."
他们会重新装上钻头
Going to be retrofitted with your drilling arm.
在无重力状态 有八百匹涡轮马力
She'll turn 800 turbo horses in nearzero gravity.
让我们看看
Mind if we take a look at her now?
把塑料管拆掉 麦斯，动手吧
All these rubber hoses gotta go, Max. Count 'em up.
我们要变速器
Make sure it's shortthrow shifters.
告诉我这是什么？
Quincy! Somebody tell me what this is.
塑料冰淇淋勺子吗？是不是花了四百块？
Plastic ice cream scoop? What'd that cost? About $400.
我服役这么多年 没见过你们这么差的人
This is about the sorriest group of people I've seen in all my entire military career.
太空飞行会让你们惊声尖叫
Your space flight's gonna be a brutal assault on your senses.
我让你们先尝尝苦头
I'm here to give you a taste of that.
太空总署有全世界最顶尖的飞行员
NASA's got some of the finest pilots in the world.
他们保证会让你们脑袋充血
They're gonna be suckin' your eyes into the back of your heads.
飞慢点，这是我的第一次
Go easy on me, okay? It's my first time.
老实说，我有点怕坐飞机
I just wanna seriously say I have a small fear of flying.
我要让你们旋转
I'm gonna twist ya.  [Screaming Continues]
-倒转 -你在搞什么？
I'm gonna flip ya.  What's the matter with you?
把你们晃得全身酸痛
Frap your body till your bones hurt.
要是你们尖叫 我们就飞得更快
When you squeal, I'm just gonna go faster and harder.
让我下去
No, take me down! [Screaming]
其他人怎样？
How's the rest of the crew?  Well, uh
抱歉我吐在你的仪表板上
Sorry about the rib chunks all over your dashboard.
我们得拍X光
Don't forget: We gotta Xray all these
“星球大战”里你最想当谁？
If you had to say, who would you say?  I don't know, Oscar.
-不晓得，你呢？ -韩苏洛
-Who do you think you are?  -Han Solo.
我一定是韩苏洛
No, if anybody's anybody, I'm Han.
你是邱巴卡
And you're you're Chewbacca.
拜托！你看过“星球大战”吗？
Chewie? Have you even seen Star Wars?
1969年 阿姆斯特朗能在月球上弹跳
Neil Armstrong, 1969, bouncing on the moon.
那是因为 月球的重力比地球小
He's bouncing up there because there's less gravity up there than on Earth.
在陨石上也一样，小心点
This will be similar to the asteroid, so watch it.
要是在上面用力弹跳
Something gets launched off that asteroid with enough force,
就可能会漂到外太空
it's gonna keep on going right into outer space.
你是不是也觉得 华特很性感？
What is the deal? Is it just me, or is Watts really hot?
是啊
Yeah.
新的太空衣有定向推进器
We have these new generation suits with directional accelerant thrusters.
你不会漂到外太空
You won't bounce like Neil Armstrong.  Yeah, think so?
-大熊 -是
Bear!  Yes?
-你有问题吗？ -没有
Do we have a problem?  No.
我正在讲解定向推进器 怎么能让你留在地面上
'Cause I'm trying to describe to you how these D.A.T.s keep your ass on the ground.
万一我踢你一脚
So that if I were to kick you in the balls,  Ooh.
你又不会用推进器 你会怎样？
and you don't know how to work them, what happens to you?
-漂到外太空 -没错
-I float away.  -Yeah.
这个训练几时开始？
And when do we start training for that?
我给你们30秒戴好头盔
Gentlemen, I'll give you 30 seconds to put your helmets on.
然后把氧气吸光
Then the oxygen will be sucked out of this vacuum,
你们就会知道在外太空的滋味了
and you will know what it's like to be in space. Go!
30秒后减压
[Man On P.A.] Depressurize in 30 seconds.
打开主阀门
Main valves have been activated.
真空状态
“6天11小时”
各位，这就是飞行计划
Okay, gentlemen, so here's the flight plan.
大家别笑 我知道这不合比例
Now let's keep the laughter to a minimum. I know this is not to scale.
两艘航天飞机将于周二傍晚六点半发射
Both shuttles will take off Tuesday at 6:30 p.m.
67分钟后
Now 67 minutes later,
到俄国空间站和宇航员安卓普会合
you're gonna dock with the Russian space station to meet cosmonaut Andropov...
他会替航天飞机加液化氧
who will refuel the shuttles with liquid O2.
那就是燃料
That's your fuel. Then you'll release...
然后再花六十小时飞到月球
and take a 60hour trip toward the moon.
只有一个机会能登陆陨石
Now we only have one shot of landing on this rock,
那就是当陨石经过月球的时候
and that's precisely when the asteroid passes by the moon.
利用月球引力和火箭推力
You'll then use lunar gravity and burn your thrusters,
让航天飞机绕过月球
slingshotting you around the moon,
飞到陨石后面
coming up behind the asteroid.
-这时的重力将达到11G -我记得这段
-You'll be upward of 11 Gs.  -Yeah, I remember this one.
大灰狼被绑在火箭上
It's where the coyote sat his ass down in a slingshot...
用大弹弓把自己射出去
and he strapped himself to an Acme rocket.
-我们也是这样吗？ -色狼
Isls that what we're doin' here?  Rockhound.
我很认真，因为大灰狼的下场很惨
No, no, really, because it didn't work out too well for the coyote, Harry.
我相信我们的火箭 比大灰狼的好
[Overlapping Chattering]  Actually, we have a lot better rockets than the coyote.
完成这个动作以后
Now when you've finished...
航天飞机
your Road Runner thrust move,
就以22500英里的时速
you'll be moving at 22,500 miles per hour.
飞向那颗陨石后面
Coming around behind the asteroid,
希望这时月球引力 已经吸掉陨石尾部
where we're hoping that the tail debris will be cleared by the moon's gravity.
让你们顺利降落在这里
And you'll land right here. That's it.
两艘航天飞机分别降落在
We got separate landing sites for each team.
地质条件最好的地方
Softest parts of the rock as we can figure.
我们准备两组人马 太空总署绝不冒险
At NASA, we don't take chances. We double up on everything.
谁先钻到八百英尺谁就赢
First team that hits 800 feet wins.
陨石很大，有重力 应该可以行走
Now this rock is big, dense. It's got some gravity. You can walk around,
不过还是用定向推进器比较轻松
but use your thrusters so you can work easier.
楚门先生，要是成功降落
Okay, Mr. Truman, let's say that we actually do land on this.
上面会是什么情况？
What's it gonna be like up there?
阳光下200度，背光处零下200度
Two hundred degrees in the sunlight. Minus 200 in the shade.
布满尖石的峡谷、重力不稳定
Canyons of razorsharp rock. Unpredictable gravitational conditions.
地面会突然喷发，大概就是这样
Unexpected eruptions. Things like that.
也就是最可怕的环境
Okay, so the scariest environment imaginable. Thanks.
你这么说我就懂了 最可怕的环境
That's all you gotta say: scariest environment imaginable.
你们钻好洞 放下核弹就离开
Okay, so you drill, you drop the nuke and you leave.
最重要的是
Now here's the key. You're gonna remote detonate the bomb...
要在陨石到达这里之前 就用摇控器引爆核弹
before the asteroid passes this plane, zero barrier.
这是最后屏障
You do that, and the remaining pieces of rock...
这样一来陨石碎片就会擦肩而过
should be deflected enough to pass right by us.
要是突破最后屏障才引爆
Now if the bomb explodes after zero barrier,
一切都完了
game's over.
这是休斯顿，发射火箭
Paul, this is Houston, fire your rockets!
全速前进
[Imitating Rocket Blasting]  Okay, your rockets are maximum.
-奥斯卡 -哈瑞，怎么了？
Oscar!  Hey, Harry. Hey, how's it goin'?
你看到葛瑞丝吗？
Have you seen Grace?
她跟小杰在停机棚
Yeah, she's over in the hangar with A.J.
等等，你说葛瑞丝吗？ 我还以为你是说大熊
Harry, wait a second. Did you say Grace? Okay, I thought you said Bear.
你原意嫁给我吗？
Will you marry me?
哈瑞，她都能投票了
Grace is old enough to vote, Harry.
她也能喝酒、结婚和离婚
She's old enough to drink or get married if she wants to, get a divorce.
我告诉你们
Let me tell you something, fellas.
等我完成任务回到地球
When I get back, when we get this job done,
我会用自己的方法处理这件事
I will deal with this in my own way.
我不是替小杰说话
Come on, Harry. It's not like I'm rootin' for A.J. here.
我只是说她不是小孩子了
I'm just sayin', Grace is not a little girl any more.  Hey, Rock.
等等，色狼 我去拿笔
Wait a minute. Let me get a pencil and a piece of paper.
记下你的金玉良言
I wanna jot down all your pearls of wisdom here.
老实说，当我们到处奔波时
Get serious, Harry. Come on. While we're off trottin' the globe, hunting mud,
她已经长得亭亭玉立了
Gracie grew up to become a fullblown hottie, you know?
-她是个大美女 -超级辣妹
-Harry, she is fully hot. -She is  She's a babe.
拜托！你们说的是我女儿
Max, okay, you're talkin' about my little girl, all right?
我对她很了解，好吗？
I think I know who and what she is, okay?
我们只是说 你女儿长大了
Harry, all we're sayin' is, we're talkin' about a kid who's comin' into her own right now.
-她对身体很好奇 也会探索性欲 -你知道吗？
-She's gettin' curious about her body, and she's exploring her sexuality.  -You know what?
这很自然
Oscar.  That's a natural thing.
你只比她大五分钟 我干嘛听你的
You are about five minutes older than Grace is. Why should I listen to you?
因为我知道荷尔蒙
I know what it feels like to have your hormones pullin' you in just...
会让人把持不住
a thousand different directions.
你不要介意 我们帮忙把她养大
No disrespect, man, but we all helped to raise her.
都拿她当女儿
So, in part, we all feel like a bunch of daddies here.
没错
That's true.
我辛苦工作这么多年 不是让我女儿嫁给一个粗人
I'll be damned if I worked all these years so my little girl can marry a roughneck.
她应该比我有出息
She's better than that.
她比我们都有出息
Better than all of us.
(穿山甲测试地点)
坐好，放轻松 我会让你大开眼界
Harry, just sit back, relax. I'm gonna put on a free Armadillo driving clinic.
两艘航天飞机都有钻洞小组
Two shuttle teams.
小杰、奥斯卡、费弟和大熊 负责独立号的钻头
A.J.'ll be running the drill team with Oscar, Bear and Noonan on the Independence.
我、奇克、麦斯和色狼 负责自由号的钻头
I'll run the drill team on Freedom with Chick, Rockhound and Max.
登陆后只有八个钟头钻洞
Once we land, we'll have eight hours to get the job done.
我们得钻八百英尺 才能把陨石炸成两半
In order to split this rock on the fault line, we're gonna have to drill to 800 feet.
大家准备好了 开始进行水底模拟训练
Let's get our game faces on. Now it's time for underwater simulation.
独立号加油，快点 我们是青年队，年轻力壮
[A.J.] Come on. Let's keep it up. Let's go. We're the younger team here.
转速加到一万一千
We're on the varsity team. Take it to 11,000.
我们要考考他
Okay, gentlemen, we're gonna trick 'em up. My computer will simulate...
在625英尺模拟天然气层,635英尺模拟铁氧层
a gas pocket at 625 feet and then hard iron ferrite at 635.
我要增加液化氧,加速吧
I'm gonna drill some more. We're takin' her up.
-我要加强动力 -不错，慢慢来
I'm givin' it more torque right now.  All right, lookin' good, Bear.
注意时间，独立号
Clamp it down. Watch your time, Independence team.
谢了，哈瑞 让我自己作主
Thanks, Harry. Would you mind lettin' me run my own team?
变速器会爆，慢一点
You're gonna blow the tranny. Slow it down, baby.  Take it easy, Bear.
放心，大熊，没问题
Just relax. She can handle it.
到了六百英尺，钻管太长 把转速减到八千
A.J., you're at 600 feet. Your pipe is long. Let's back the R.P.M.s down to 8,000.
没有时间了
We don't have time for 8,000!  A.J., take it back down.
要是你不减低转速 钻管或是变速器就会爆掉
You're gonna snap the pipe. I don't wanna blow this transmission.
-可恶，一万一千 -慢一点，小杰
Damn it, 11,000.  Slow it down, A.J.
大熊，有点志气
Bear, come on. Get on our team for a little bit.
太空牛仔
Oh, space cowboy.
-你听到吗？ -我在听
-Harry, are you listenin' to this?  -Yeah, I'm listenin', Bear.
别管哈瑞，你要听我的
You don't work for Harry any more, okay? Out there, you gotta listen to me.
在陨石上面是我作主
When we're on that rocket, you gotta do what I say.
转速加到一万一
I'm throttling up to another 1,000.
别冲动，变速器会爆掉
A.J., back it off. You're gonna blow the transmission.
哈瑞，让我决定
Hey, Harry, would you let me run my team, please?
转速太高
R.P.M.s are at red line.  Bear, goddamn it, I know what I'm doing.
我知道状况，机器没问题 相信我
Come on. She can handle this. She'll be fine. Trust me.
-小杰，听好 -一号变速器爆掉了
-A.J., back down.  -The number one transmission is down.
电脑搞错了，我没有做错
Oh, son of a The computer's wrong, and you know that.
我们要重新来一次
We did the right thing.  We're gonna restart the simulation.
你想换人就要趁早
If you wanna replace a member of the crew, now is the time.
我会处理的,奇克，叫他们出来
I'll take care of this. Get him out of the tank, Chick.
-你想回家吗？ 你想被开除吗？ -不想，
-You wanna go home? Is that it? You wanna be fired?  -No, I don't.
-我的小组没有做错 -你的小组？
-My crew was doing the right thing.  -Your crew?
你的小组把变速器爆掉了
Yeah.  Your crew just blew the transmission, A.J.!
电脑太小心了
Listen, that NASA computer is just playin' it safe.
你设计的钻头承受得住
The machine you built the rig could do it.
闭嘴，给我闭嘴
Shut up. Just shut up! Shut your mouth!
那些人绝对不会让你凭着直觉为所欲为
Those men in that room have zero tolerance for showin' off, hot doggin',
或是逞英雄，明白吗？
goin' by your gut instinct or you tryin' to be a hero, you got that?
-说话啊，小杰 -我明白了
-Say the words, A.J.!  -I got it!
-我要他们明天休息一天 -休息，什么意思？
-I want my men to have tomorrow night off.  -What do you mean "off"?
放松，好好地休息十个钟头,然后再出发到佛罗里达
I mean, off. Out of here. For at least ten hours. Then we'll go to Kennedy.
这是不可能的，太冒险了
Well, there's no possible way we can do that, Harry.
他们也许会泄密
There's a potentially huge security risk. What if they talk?
-或者是受伤 -他们也许会太紧张办不了事
-What if they get hurt?  -What if they're too burnt out to do the right thing?
或是忘了这项任务的目的
What if they get up there, and they forget what they're fighting for?
你也看到，他们就快崩溃了
You see what's goin' on. These boys are ready to snap.
他们并不想去 只是逼不得已
They didn't ask to be here. They got pulled off the street.
明天很可能是他们在地球上的最后一天
For all we know, tomorrow night could be the last night they ever see Earth.
让他们陪陪家人并不过份吧
I don't think it's too much to ask to let 'em spend it with their families.
-这是不可能的 -你有家人吧，上校？
Listen, there's no possible way we can do that.  You got family, Colonel?
-两个女儿 -难道你不想陪陪她们吗？
Two girls.  Wouldn't you like to spend tomorrow with your girls?
这不是请求，我要你照办
I'm not askin' ya. I'm tellin' ya.
我要你想办法
Make this happen.
你借这么多钱，难道不数一下吗？
This is a pretty big loan. Why don't you count the cash?
不用了，这里看起来有十万元
Nah, this looks like 100 grand to me.
当然了，我要收六成利息 你最好小心点
I'm givin' you this at 60 percent. I hope you know what you're doin',
要是我拿不到钱 就会敲碎你的脑袋
because I'll bust your head with a sledgehammer.
-放心啦，我会还钱的 -我看你的气色很差
-You'll get your money back.  -You don't look too healthy.
你不会死掉吧？
You're not gonna die on me, are ya?
我们都可能会死,谢了
Let's just say, no more than you are. Thanks, Vic.
* Don't wanna close my eyes *
* I don't wanna fall asleep *
* 'Cause I'd miss you, baby *
* And I don't wanna miss a thing *
-你知道我在想什么吗？ -什么？
-You know what I was thinkin'?  -What?
我认为动物饼干不算咸饼干
I really don't think that the animal cracker qualifies as a cracker.
-为什么？ -因为是甜的
-Why?  -Well, 'cause it's sweet, which to me suggests cookie.
咸饼干
And, you know, putting cheese on something is sort of the defining characteristic...
通常都放乳酪
of what makes a cracker a cracker.
我突然想到的
I don't know why I thought of that. I just
你真会甜言蜜语
Baby, you have such sweet pillow talk.
这算是饼干动物奇观
I got a little animal cracker, Discovery Channel thing happenin' right here.
羚羊在平原上吃草
Watch the gazelle, as he grazes through the open plains.
现在印度豹偷偷爬过去
Now look, as the cheetah approaches.
看它怎么跟踪猎物
Watch, as he stalks his prey.
羚羊有所警觉
Now, the gazelle's a little spooked,
它可以向北
and he could head north to the ample sustenance...
逃到两座山峰之间丰沃的草原
provided by the mountainous peaks above.
它也可以逃往南方
He could go south.
这时羚羊面对最困难的抉择
The gazelle now faces man's most perilous question:
北
North...
或南
or south?
神秘的处女地
Way down under.
下周请继续收看
Tune in next week.  [Giggling]
你想现在这个世界上
do you think it's possible that anyone else in the world...
有人也像我们这样吗？
is doing this very same thing at this very same moment?
希望有
I hope so.
要不然我们拯救地球干嘛？
Otherwise, what the hell are we tryin' to save?
* Don't wanna close my eyes *
* I don't wanna fall asleep 'cause I'd miss you, baby *
* And I don't wanna miss a thing **
你怎么来了？
What are you doing here?
我正好路过…
I was just passin' by on the, uh
想来…
I came
他是谁？
Who's he?
他是个推销员
That man's a salesman.
孩子，进屋去好么
Would you go inside?
谢谢
Thank you.
他长高了
He got big.  [Door Closes]
你不能随便跑来 法院禁止你来访
You can't come around like this. The court says you can't.
-这对他不好 -我知道，我…
-It confuses him.  -No, I know. I just
我只想说…
I wanted to say...
对不起，
that I'm sorry...
很抱歉
about everything.
我要做一件事，一件大事
I got somethin' comin' up. It's somethin' kinda big.
也许你会以我为荣
You just might be proud of me.
请你把这个给他
Would you do somethin' for me? Would you just give him this?
你不必说是我给的
You don't have to You don't have to tell him who it's from. Just
* Everybody talkin' about what it is, what it ain't *
* Kiss on the devil and you piss off a saint *
* But it can't be love if you don't have to crawl *
* You say you only love him but you got to have it all *
费弟，你要一万块吗？
Hey, Noonan, you need ten grand?
总得替她们付学费吧
We gotta put these girls through college.
当宇航员真爽
I love this astronaut stuff.
这是个好差事
Good work, if you can get it.
我是来接受宇航员训练的
Yeah, I'm just in town doin' a little astronaut training.
太空英雄
Ooh! Astronauta.
我是任务专家
Ah, si. I'm a mission specialist.
-那是什么意思？ -不知道
Yes, and what's that mean?  I don't know.
你们算是什么东西，
Hey! Who the hell do you think you guys are?
竟敢这么嚣张？
You're hoggin' all the action.  Hey, pinhead.
傻瓜，去玩自己吧
Why don't you go find your own party?
别这么自私
Why don't you spread the wealth, pal?
你这缩头乌龟
Here. Why don't you go buy yourself a neck?
秃头佬
Hey, Mr. Clean!
去问问太空总署 我们是宇航员
Call NASA! They'll confirm it! We're astronauts!  Get over there. Yeah, yeah.
-我们是宇航员 -我们全都是宇航员
-Yeah, we're astronauts!  -Yeah, we're all astronauts.
事关国家安全 明天一早你就被开除了
You are so messing with national security right now, man. You are fired tomorrow morning.
我要去找中情局和调查局
I'm telling ya. I'll get the C.I.A. and the F.B.I.
你只能去当玩具城的警卫
You'll be workin' security at Toys 'R' Us.
再见，太空英雄
Oh, oh, baby, no, no. No, no!  Byebye, little astronaut.
不要走,我要上太空不再回来了
Oh, don't leave, baby. No, no, no. See, I'm goin' into space, and I'm not comin' back.
它的时速三万英里
It's coming in at 30,000 miles an hour!
-它会撞到哪里？ -东亚,11分钟
-Give me a projected impact.  -East Asia, 11 minutes.
-我们得警告… -警告谁？整个东南亚吗？
-We're gonna have to warn  -Warn who? The entire South Pacific?
“陨石危机公开”
全世界都知道了
So the whole world knows.
告诉我你没有让人失望过
Tell me you've never let anybody down before.
我没有放弃过，怎么样？
I never quit yet.
只好这样了
ow's that?  I guess that'll have to do.
你知道吗？
You know somethin'?
我还记得我进来的第一年
I still remember the first, middle and last name...
每个宇航员的姓名
of every guy that qualified for the astronaut programme first year I was here.
我却只能进工程部 这是没办法的
Thanks. I went into the engineering programme. Kinda had to.
可是我好想上太空
But boy, I wanted to go up there.
我想在衣袖别上宇航员臂章
I wanted to be one of those guys with a mission patch on my arm.
我很想跟你一起上去
I tell you, I'd be on that shuttle with you, Harry, if I could.
你和我都不想上去
You don't want to be up in that shuttle any more than I do.
祝你明天好运
Good luck in Florida tomorrow.
有五万人丧命…
[Female Newscaster #1] The death of 50,000 people in Shanghai yesterday has rattled
法国卫星探测到…
[Male Newscaster #1] A French satellite has tracked an object in space
(佛罗里达肯尼迪太空中心)
海啸高达五百英尺
[Female Newscaster #2] Sources are estimating that the tidal wave was five
CNN在佛罗里达为您报导
[Male Newscaster #2] This is CNN, live in Florida.
太空总署进入军事戒备
We have just learned that NASA is on a fullscale military alert.
这叫做地球杀手
They're calling this a global killer.
美国政府保持沉默
[Female Newscaster #3] The government has been very tightlipped throughout this
五角大厦和太空总署合作
[Female Newscaster #4] The Pentagon is getting involved at this point...
可能要出航天任务
with some kind of a project involving NASA and perhaps a shuttle mission
国防部官员不愿澄清
Senior Pentagon officials refused comment, adding fuel to the speculation...
这令人怀疑事态严重
that there could be a very serious problem.
一组特别的宇航员 今晚抵达佛罗里达
[Truman] We have a special team of astronauts that arrived in Florida this evening.
准备开始发射程序
NASA's in emergency launch preparation in cooperation with Russian, Japanese...
美国和法俄日等国 合作进行史上规模最大的太空任务
and French space agencies on the most massive joint space venture in history.
“发射时间倒数:12小时”
葛瑞丝
Gracie?
我看到你的纸条
Got your note.
你在这里干嘛？
What're you doin' out here, honey?  Um, just thinkin'.
想事情
Yeah.
我要向你道歉
I, um, want to apologize to you for
不，你不必道歉
Oh, no, Grace, stop. You don't have to apologize at all.
我不该把你带到油井，到处奔波
II sh I shouldn't have dragged you around on all those oil rigs.
我对不起你
I don't think that I did the right thing with you.
不，我爱这种生活
You're wrong. I love my life.
我爱我生活中的一切
I love everything about my life.
妈妈离开我并不怪你
And I don't blame you for my mother leaving.
是她抛弃我们俩
She left us both.
我爱你
And I love you.
别说你不会回来
And don't talk like you're not comin' back.
答应我你一定会回来
Promise me that you'll come back.
-好 -说“我保证”
-Okay.  -Say, "I promise."
我保证
I promise, Grace.
不会有事的，葛瑞丝
It's gonna be all right, Grace.
如果你不嫌麻烦的话
If it's not too much trouble,
请你顺便把我未婚夫带回来
can you please bring my fiance home with you?
老天
Oh, Jesus.
“纪念阿波罗一号壮烈牺牲的太空英雄”
总统一小时后发表讲话并回答记者提问
The president will be addressing the nation and all of you personally within the hour.
“造福全人类”
宇航员，来吧
Astronauts.
过几天见
I'll see you in a couple days, honey.
*收拾行囊*
* All my bags are packed *
*准备出发*
* I'm ready to go *
*呆呆站在你家大门*
* I'm standin' here outside your door *  ** [Humming]
*我不忍心将你叫醒*
* I hate to wake you up *
*向你道别*
* To say goodbye *
*亲我一下对我微笑*
* So kiss me and smile for me *
*让我知道你会等我*
* Let me know you'll wait for me *
*紧抱着我别让我走*
* Hold me like you'll never let me go *
*我要搭机*
[Grunting] * 'Cause I'm leavin' *
*远离家乡*
* On a jet plane *
*我不晓得何时回来*
* Don't know when I'll be back again *
*搭机远离家乡*
* Leavin' on a jet plane *
*不知何时回来*
* I don't know when I'll be back again *
*搭机远离家乡*
* Leavin' on a jet plane *
*不知何时回来…*
* I don't know when I'll be back again *
-*搭机远离家乡,不知何时回来…* -你瞧，楚门
-* Leavin' on a jet plane Don't know when I'll be back again *  -So, Truman,
你就找来这群小丑拯救地球吗？
this is who you found to save the planet.
-可以走了吧 -等一下
-Frost, you good to go?  -Mmhmm. One One sec.
*搭机远离家乡* -他老是吊儿郎当的
* Leavin' on a jet plane *  That boy don't take anything seriously.
是呀，我记得你当年也一样
Yeah. Reminds me of a guy I used to know.
*搭机远离家乡*
* Aah *  * Leavin' on a jet plane *
-*不知何时回来…* -我会娶你的
-* I don't know when I'll be back again *  -I'm marrying you.
-当然了 -*搭机远离家乡*
Bet your ass you are.  * Leavin' on a jet plane *
*不知何时回来…*
* I don't know when I'll be back again **
今晚
I address you tonight,
我不是以美国总统的身份向各位发言
not as the President of the United States,
我也不是一国元首
not as the leader of a country,
而是人类的一员
but as a citizen of humanity.
人类面对最大的挑战
We are faced with the very gravest of challenges.
圣经说这是世界末日 万物毁灭
The Bible calls this day Armageddon, the end of all things.
不过这是地球史上
And yet, for the first time...
人类首次
in the history of the planet,
凭自己的力量
a species has the technology...
避免遭到毁灭
to prevent its own extinction.  [Translator On TV]
我要让大家知道
All of you praying with us need to know...
我们已经尽一切努力
that everything that can be done to prevent this disaster...
避免这场浩劫
is being called into service.
人类追求的
The human thirst for excellence,
知识结晶
[Translator On Radio]  knowledge,
对科学的苦心钻研
every step up the ladder of science,
冒险飞向太空的努力
every adventurous reach into space,
现代科技的成果和想像力,甚至来自战争的经验
all of our combined modern technologies and imaginations, even the wars that we've fought,
都为这场生死战
have provided us the tools...
提供武器
to wage this terrible battle.
在多灾多难的历史上 人类曾经犯过多少错
Through all the chaos that is our history,  [Translator On TV]
人们曾经受过多少苦 经过这么多年
through all of the wrongs and the discord, through all of the pain and suffering,
只有一种情操…
through all of our times, there is one thing that has...
-妈妈，那个推销员上电视了
nourished our souls...  Mom, that salesman's on TV.
…能让人类继续生存下去
and elevated our species above its origins,
那就是勇气
and that is our courage.
全世界的希望
Dreams of an entire planet are focused tonight...
都寄托在这十四名勇士身上
on those 14 brave souls...
他们将飞向太空
travelling into the heavens.
他不是推销员，
That man's not a salesman.
-他是你爸爸 -让全球的人类目睹
-That's your daddy.  -And may we all,
你们的英勇事迹
citizens the world over, see these events through.
愿上帝保佑，祝你们好运
Godspeed and good luck to you.
自由号、独立号
Freedom crew. Independence crew.
-你还好吧？ -还好
-How ya feelin'?  -Uh, good, you know.
我这辈子没这么害怕过
I mean, considering I've never been this scared in my entire life. I You know
上去了你就得靠自己
Listen. Once you get up there, you're gonna be on your own.
-要是发生什么事… -我知道，哈瑞
-If anything should happen, I just wanted to  -I know, Harry.
我会试着不让你失望
I'll, uh, try not to disappoint you.
你要保重，小子
Take care of yourself, kid.
自由号到了
[Man #1] Freedom's on the bridge. Attention in the firing room.
-注意了，氧化剂完成输入 -独立号到了
Oxidizer loading is complete.  [Man #2] Independence on the bridge.
请注意，倒数计时两小时
[Man #1] Attention all personnel. We are T minus two hours to the programme goal.
-哈瑞 -怎么了？
-Hey, Harry.  -Yeah, Rock?
这里有四百万磅燃料 一枚核弹
You know, we're sittin' on four million pounds of fuel, one nuclear weapon...
和一个庞大复杂的钻头
and a thing that has 270,000 moving parts...
由出价最低的承包商制造
built by the lowest bidder. [Grunts]
-真是让人放心，对吧？ -是啊
-Makes you feel good, doesn't it?  -Yeah.
-你觉得如何，奥斯卡？ -很棒
-How ya doin', Oscar?  -Great.
我既兴奋又害怕
I got that excited, scared feelin'
九成兴奋，一成害怕
like 98 percent excited, 2 percent scared.
也许正好相反,也许是九成害怕，一成兴奋
Maybe more. It could be 2 It could be 98 percent scared, 2 percent excited.
所以我才这么激动紧张 我也搞不清楚
But that's what makes it so intense, is it's so confused. I can't really figure it out.
请绑紧点，我不想掉下来
Will you make mine really tight, 'cause I don't want to fall out?
最好紧得快要把我勒死
I mean, almost to the point of cutting off circulation.
要是太空总署倒闭
It must be a comfort to know that if the space programme goes under,
你可以去当驯兽师
you can always get a job at Helga's House of Pain, huh?
这里是发射中心 报告准备情况
All right. Flight directors on with the go/nogo for launch.
-返航？推进器？ -就绪 -就绪
Retro. Booster.  Go flight.  Go flight.
-导航系统？程序小组？ -就绪 -就绪
Ecos. Trajectory.  Go flight.  Go flight.
救援系统？
FIDO. EVA.  Go flight.  Go flight.
-自由号通讯系统？ 独立号通讯系统？-就绪
CAPCOM Freedom. CAPCOM Independence.  Go flight.
-就绪 -各位，一切就绪
Go flight.  All right, ladies and gentlemen, it's pucker time.
自由号和独立号 这是发射中心 倒数计时一分钟
Independence and Freedom, this is Kennedy firing room. We're T minus one minute.
大家把护镜放下来
All crew members, close and lock your visors.
独立号，系统一切正常
Independence, this is launch control. Be advised, we're in a smooth count.
倒数31秒，启动自动程序
T minus 31. You're go for autosequence start.
飞行员，启动辅助电源
P.L.T.s, perform your A.P.U. prestart.
各位，你们都是战士.上帝保佑你们
Okay, gentlemen, you're our warriors up there. God be with you.
你们都是英雄 好好享受这一趟
You're already heroes. Just sit back and enjoy the ride.
倒数20秒
We're T minus 20 seconds.
Ten. Nine. Eight. Seven.
Four. Three. Two. One.
主引擎启动
[Roaring]  We have main engine start.
点燃推进火箭
We have booster ignition.  We're going.
And liftoff.
Freedom, this is flight deck.  [Sharp On Radio]
情况不错
Roger, Freedom. You're looking good.
独立号准备发射 -三、二、一
We have go for Independence.  Three. Two. One.
升空
Independence, we have booster ignition.  [Chattering Continues]
升空了，休斯顿
We have liftoff.  We are cooking, Houston.
休斯顿，发射成功 交给你们了
Houston, the tower is clear. They're all yours.
打起精神，我们接手
[Shuttles Roaring]  Heads up, everybody. They're ours now.
-引擎运作正常 -两艘航天飞机都要注意
-All engines are go.  -Keep a sharp eye out on both of 'em.
进行翻转动作
[Sharp] Start roll manoeuvre.
翻转成功,很顺利,最高压力
Two good roll programmes.  One down.  Independence, we have max cue.
现在达到最高压力
Roger, Control. We are a max cue.
抛弃固体火箭推进器
S.R.B. sep  [Engines Roaring]
-切断主引擎 -收到
-We are singleengine, press, demigo.  -Copy, press, demigo.
休斯顿，这趟真过瘾
Houston, this is a kickass ride!
自由号，主引擎按时切断
Freedom, this is Houston. Main engine cut out on schedule. Out.
自由号,状态很好
Freedom, stats are good.
我的天
Independence, telemetry is up and running.  Oh, my God.
-这是太空 -还不算什么
-This is space! -'Course, we're just in the beginning part of space.
我们都还没到外太空
WeWe haven't gotten to outer space yet.
我看到空间站了 点燃减速火箭
Roger, Houston. We have a visual on the Russian space station. Initiating retro burn.
各位，空间站在外太空 已经有十一年了
Gentlemen, remember the Russian space station has been up there for 11 years.
我们的车都没这么旧
Most of us don't have cars that old.
宇航员在里头待了一年半 只有一个人
Now, the cosmonaut on board has been on that tin can for 18 months, alone.
他一定会有点古怪
So don't be surprised if he's a little... off.
各位，
Independence, we're gonna put you  All right, crew.
脱掉飞行衣
Let's exit these flight suits.  [Laughing]
大家好，
[Russian Accent] Hello.
这是俄国空间站 听到吗？
This is Russian space station. Can you hear me?
你好，我们收到 这是休斯顿
[Speaks Russian] We copy, Russian space station. This is Houston.
我准备启动推进器
I'm ready to fire my thrusters any time.
-请待命 -我哪儿都不会去
-Stand by.  -Okay. I'm not going anywhere.
一切就绪，进行重力旋转
We have a go. Initiate gravitational spin.
完成百分之四十旋转
You are maxed at 40percent spin.  [Moans]
好了，休斯顿
Okay, Houston.
我开始感觉有重力了
I can feel I'm having gravity.
各位，马上就要连接
All right, gentlemen. We're gonna dock in a minute.
俄国空间站有模拟重力
Now, the Russian space station has fired her rockets...
这样工作起来比较快
Whee!  to simulate gravity and let us work faster.
不过你们会有点想吐 要有心理准备
It's gonna make you queasy, so prepare yourself.
该是时候了 我有一个钟头没吐过
Well, it's about time. I haven't thrown up in about an hour.  [Laughing]
进行连接程序
Initiating first phase of docking procedure.
换到手控 手控
Switching to manual.  Manual override.
每秒一英尺，慢慢来 二十英尺
One foot per second. Let's take this slow and do it right, folks. Twenty feet.
十英尺
[Blipping]  Ten feet.
情况很好 五英尺
Looking good on radar. Five feet.
锁住，燃料组，快走
Locks are engaged. Fuel teams, let's go.
自由号一切顺利
Freedom, telemetry is looking good.
暂时连接
[Hissing]  We have soft dock.
燃料组，准备出航天飞机
[Sharp] Fuel teams, prepare to unload.
各位，小心头
All right, gentlemen, watch your heads.
走吧，独立号
Let's go, Independence.
上校
Colonel.
他人呢？有人在吗？
Where is he? Anybody home?
欢迎，伙计们
Welcome, everybody!
这里不是加油站.这是我负责的先进实验室
I am not gas station. This is sophisticated laboratory. I'm in charge.
什么也别乱碰
So do not be touching anything.
我要…你
I need one I need you.  Go with him.
-跟他去 -快点，快点，来吧
I need you. Hurry up. Hurry up. Come on. Come on.
你得盯着燃料仪表 穿上防冻衣
It's very important you watch the fuel gauge, okay? Put on cold suit.
收到了，准备输送燃料
Copy that, Houston. Prepping for fuel transfer.
燃料管在下面
Fuel pod is down there.
下面？太好了
It's down here, huh? Great.
把这些接起来
Okay, let's connect these fuel lines.
自由号，左，独立号，右
Freedom on the left, Independence on the right.
我们到左边
All right. We're goin' left here.
这是燃料仪表，看好它 150、160没问题
To the right is fuel gauge. You watch the fuel gauge. One fifty, okay.
跳到200，太空站就完了
One sixty, okay. Two hundred, bad disaster for space station.
跳到200就喊勒夫 把这个打开，叫勒夫
So if you watch 200, you call for Lev, on, and you see here number one. Off.
然后拉下这个，拉到底
You ask for Lev. And you pull this down, all the way down.
-勒夫是什么？ -我就是勒夫，俄国太空上校
-What's Lev?  -I am Lev Andropov, colonel of Russian space agency.
在俄国是大人物
In Russia I'm a very big man.
准备输送燃料
We're ready to transfer.  I'm coming. No problem.
我来了，没问题
You. You. You there!
锁住,准备输送燃料
Hard locked.  Ready for transfusion!
燃料输送中
[Lev] Fuel is pumping.
勒夫，压力上升，
Hey, Lev, the, uh, thethe pressure's climbing.
有问题了
Still, we're on fuel transference.
别碰我叔叔
Don't touch my uncle. You know?
他是我们家的天才
He's a genius of my family.
有人听到吗？
[Hissing]  Lev! Can anybody hear me? Guys? Hello, guys!
他专门做核弹
[No Audio]  He used to work for a big bomb factory.
瞄准纽约
He used to make the tip of the bomb, the thing...
或是华府就轰掉
that finds, uh, New York or Washington, you know?
有温差，检查管子
Ooh.  Check your hoses. We got some thermal variation.
检查联轴器 我要回航天飞机
Stamper, let's look at the couplings, back on the shuttle.
好，关掉
Okay. Shut down. Uh
大伙儿
Uh Guys!
什么声音？
[Sharp] What's that noise?
糟了，停下来！
Oh, no! God!
怎么了？
What is it?
燃料外泄
[Shouting In Russian] Leak! Leak!
快把他们带回航天飞机 快走
Get your men back to the shuttle! Go!
快点，快走吧
Go! Hurry up! Get out of there!
真是聪明,扳下手柄
You know, this really smarts!  Pull lever!
就是这个？
This is the lever!
-上校，快把他救出来 -小杰，快点
Colonel, we must get him out of there!  A.J., come on out!
快点，快点
Aah! Aah!  Hurry! Hurry!
进行紧急脱离
Emergency break away!
燃料舱起火
We got a fire in the fuel pod!
-快点 -小杰被困在燃料舱
-Come on!  Come on! Get in here! -A.J.'s stuck in the fuel pod!
失去控制了
We're losing it!  [All Shouting]
我看到太空站在晃动
Control, this is Independence. I am seeing vibration
-快报告 -情况不妙，燃料舱起火
-Malloy, talk to me!  -Not good. We got sparks and fire in the fuel pod.
独立号，马上离开
Independence, blow those locks and get outta there now!
解开燃料管
Dump the hoses now! We're going!
怎么回事？ 停止输送了吗？ 快爆炸了，该死
What happened? Let me shut off the O2 feed!  Harry, it's burnin' up!
麦斯，快进去
Damn! Max, Rock, get in here!
把管子弄掉
Get down there and crack these pipes over here!
我要回去救另一组人
Harry, it's burnin' up!  We're goin' back for the other team!
打开人员定位器
[Chatter On Radio]  [Man] Switch on the personnel locators.
小杰正爬上来
Trackin' A.J. He's climbin'.
太迟了，快回去，
No!  Go! Go!
快爆炸了
It's too late! Get back to the shuttle! This thing's gonna blow!
不！
No!
我们得快走，来呀
Colonel, we gotta move now! Come on! Close the hatch!
等等，里面还有人
Wait a minute! Wait a minute! We got a man in there!
打开门我们全都会死.燃料外泄
Open that door, and we'll all die!  Fuel leak!
马上撤退，快点
Evac now! Let's go! Let's go!
快回来，舱门坏了
Come on back! No, wait! The door is broken!
火势被密封在燃料舱
No!  They got the fire sealed in the fuel pod.
-火势被控制住 -快回到航天飞机
-They locked it down.  [Man On P.A.] -Tracking men to the shuttle.
还有两人被困在下面
They've still got two men trapped in there!
快跑，离航天飞机还有75英尺.其他人呢？
Keep running! The shuttle's another 75 feet! Where's the rest of the team?
小杰呢？
[All Shouting]  Where's A.J.?
-没救了 -不能丢下他
-A.J.'s gone!  -We're not leavin' without A.J.!
没救了，来不及了
He's gone! It's too late!
来吧，这是唯一的机会
Come on! This way is our only chance!
零下一百度，
So it's minus hundred!
很冷 不憋气肺会被冻僵
Very cold. Hold breath, or lung freezes!
回到航天飞机，锁上舱门
[Shouting]  Get back to the shuttle! And lock that door!
小杰还在里面 起火了 救不了他们
It's on fire! It's on fire, Harry!  It's them or all of us!
起火了
It's on fire.  Full thrust.  We're gonna get hit.
舱门会爆炸
Lev! Lev, the door's gonna blow!
我们得快走
Oh!  We're going! It's gonna blow!
小杰还在里面 快脱离 我们得快走
A.J.'s still in there!  Blow the locks. No, the bolts!  We've gotta
加油，快到了
I think we're almost there!  [All Shouting]
小杰没在独立号上 他们要锁住舱门
Flight, Independence does not have A.J. They're gonna close the door without him.
他们离航天飞机 只有75英尺远
[Man] Tracking. They're 75 feet from the shuttle.
叫他们快一点
Just tell 'em to air lock the door and go!  Dog the hatch now!
关上舱门
Close it!  [Explosion]
上校，掉下来了，快走吧
Whoa, whoa, whoa! Colonel! That thing's comin' right for We got to move!
快点，舱门快关了
Hurry up! There's the shuttle door! [Shouting]
起火了，关门
Fire's coming at us! Close the door now!
快走
Go! Go! Go!
自由号,独立号的组员全都在
Freedom, the Independence crew is on board and accounted for.
-还多了一名俄国宇航员 -成功输送九成燃料
-We're even heavy one cosmonaut.  -They got 90 percent of their fuel.
挺刺激的
Pretty intense, huh?
所以我才叫你们什么都别碰
That's why I told you, "Touch nothing."
你们这些臭牛仔
But you're bunch of cowboys.
全人类的焦点都集中在
So while the consciousness of the planet is unified,
太空总署的航天任务
focused on the NASA mission taking place right now in the vast ocean of space,
任务正进行最后阶段
[Speaking Russian]  we're now in the final hours of the mission,
两艘航天飞机准备绕过月球
as the Freedom and Independence prepare to slingshot around the moon.
“17时3分52秒”
早安，各位
Morning, guys. It's time to suit up, I guess.
穿好宇航服，准备干活
Uh, we got a big day.
18秒后中断通讯 推进程序确认
Eighteen seconds to radio interrupt.  Booster sequence confirmed.
这是休斯顿，自由号 收到了
This is Houston. Roger that, Freedom. We copy.
准备绕过月球
Shuttles are ready for the burn around the moon.
通讯中断，失去联络
Radio contact terminated. We're out.
11分钟内到达10G重力 开始祈祷吧
Nine and a half Gs for 11 minutes. I'd start praying about right now.
现在我们应该抓紧
So this is the part where we're supposed to just...
希望不会死
hold on real tight and, uh, hope we don't die.
准备越过月球轨道 进入月球轨道
Stand by for lunar roll.  High inclination. Lunar orbit.
希望你们写好遗嘱了
You boys got those wills filled out correctly?
时候到了，咬紧牙关
All right, men, this is what we trained for. Now just suck it up!
准备，5、4、
On the mark. Five. Four.
3、2、1
Three. Two. One.
-这样正常吗？ -别担心，很正常
-Is this supposed to be like this?  -Don't worry. This is normal.
你怎么知道？
How would you know? [Groaning]
时速一万四千哩 4G重力
Fourteen thousand miles an hour.  Four Gs.
-这会持续多久？ -6G
-Ahh!  How long does this last?  -Six Gs.
-时速一万五千哩 -我好重 -这不正常
Fifteen thousand.  Really heavy, man!  This isn't normal.
什么意思？ 糟糕透了
What do you mean, "this isn't normal"?  This is way worse!
8G重力，抓紧
Eight Gs. Hang tight!
-我熬不过去啦 -我们都会死的
-We're not gonna make it! -Oh, we're gonna die!
12分钟，没有信号
Twelve minutes. Flight, we still got nothin' here.
太快了
[All Groaning]  This is too fast!
10G
Ten Gs!  [Groaning Continues]
到达最高速度 时速两万两千五百哩
[Sharp] We're maxed at 22,500!
收到两艘航天飞机的信号
We have acquisition of signal from Independence and Freedom.
欢迎回来
[Relieved Chattering]  We're in, guys. All right. Welcome back, team.
我们看到目标了
We have visual of the target, Houston.
你们看到吗？
You see that?
-独立号，请回答 -休斯顿，真是不可思议
Come in, Independence.  [Sharp] Houston, you gotta see this to believe it.
-准备降落 -尾部的碎石有多少？
-Okay, team, let's take 'em in. -Okay, Quincy, how much tail debris do we have?
自由号，打开FOD雷达
[Man] Freedom, turn on FOD radar.
打开了
FOD radar on.  [Blipping]
坐好了，这会很颠簸 准备躲闪
Everybody, hang on. This could get a little rough. Engaging evasive radar.
坐好
Hold on!
该死，有浮石
Goddamn! We got debris!
抛弃辅助推进器
[Watts] We're dumping auxiliary boosters.
有乱流 好多浮石
Houston, do you read me?  We got debris!
要进去了 情况不妙
We're goin' in! We're comin' in hot!
继续前往降落点
Independence, try to maintain your present heading. You've got a target L.Z.
-浮石太多，快躲开 -不行
-There's too much debris! We gotta peel off!  -Negative!
我们被击中
[Loud Crashing]  We're hit!
求救，我失去主推进器
Mayday, mayday!  I've lost main thrusters. Get 'em back up!
求救，失去推进器
Mayday, Houston, mayday! We've lost R.C.S. thrusters!
失去控制，就快坠毁 收到吗？我们就快坠毁
Mayday, Freedom, mayday! We are out of control! We are going down!
自由号，小心
Do you read me? Freedom, we are going down!
它会撞上去
We're gonna hit!  [Blipping]
大家使用救生系统,快到货舱去
Everybody, go to your own life support! Lock yourself in the cargo bay!
我们要坠毁了 休斯顿，我们失去控制 快要坠毁了
We are going down! Houston! Houston, we are going down! We have lost control!
我戴不上去
I can't get it on!
祝你好运，自由号 我的天，完了
Good luck, Freedom.  Oh, my God, this is it.
那是什么？是独立号吗？
Sharp, what the hell is that? Is that the Independence?
独立号毁了，它没救了
[Sharp] Houston, Independence is a dead stick. They're not gonna make it.
独立号坠毁了
Houston, Independence has gone down.
准备降落，反向推动
When I touch this baby down, full reverse thrust.
给我点动力
Fires on your right, Sharp!  Reversing the thrusters!  [Thrusters Roaring]
坐好了
Hang tight! Hang tight!
休斯顿，我们错过降落点…
Houston, we overshot our landing field. We overshot our landing field.
糟糕
Oh, no!
进行系统检查 确定我们能返航
Initiate system light system check. Make sure we can still get off this rock.
电力系统损坏 启动备用系统
Our electrical system is screwed. I'm going to backup. Fuel seals check.
燃料筒密封、引擎密封、压力舱密封
Engine seals check. Pressure seals check.  Oh, God. Oh!
有人受伤吗？
Anyone hurt?  [Panting] Where's
另一艘航天飞机怎么了？ 另一艘航天飞机呢？
Where's the other shuttle? What happened to the other shuttle?
-独立号离线了 -离线？
-Independence is off the grid.  -"Off the grid"?
你是电脑吗？ 那是什么意思？
What are you, a freakin' cyborg? What does that mean?
你也看到，
Hey, you saw it yourself, right?
他们死了
They're gone.
自由号请回答
Come in, Freedom. This is CAPCOM Houston. Freedom, come in.
这是休斯顿，请回答
This is CAPCOM Houston. Come in, Freedom.
让上帝照顾我们的朋友
God!  Let's just ask God to take care of our friends.
愿他们安息 阿门
May they rest in peace.  Amen.
只有八个小时
We got eight hours.  [Gasps]
让我们完成任务回家吧
Let's get this job done and go home.
没信号，
Nothin'.
快回答吧
Come on, Watts, Sharp, somebody.
这是休斯顿
This is CAPCOM Houston.
自由号，请回答 这是休斯顿
Come in, Freedom. Freedom, come in. This is CAPCOM Houston.
-你不应该留在这里 -我已经无处可去
-Maybe you shouldn't be here.  -I don't have anywhere else to go.
自由号，请回答
Freedom, come in. This is CAPCOM Houston.
准备工具，启动钻头吧
All right, let's get the tools unpacked and fire up the Armadillo.
-惯性导航系统没反应 -我知道这是哪里
We're not getting a damn thing on the inertial nav system.  I know where we are.
-请让开 -信号中断了
Please step away. Radio signal's dead.
我要启动备用发电机
I'm flipping the backup generator.
无线电只有一半的效能
Radio signal's gonna be cut in half till we get main power back.
这里是202段第9区 15H32，差不了多少
We're in segment 202, lateral grid 9, site 15H32, give or take a few yards.
-上校错过降落点有26哩 -你怎么知道？
-Captain America here blew the landing by 26 miles.  -How the hell do you know that?
-因为我是天才 -仪表指针乱跳
-Because I'm a genius.  -The gauges will not read.
附近好像有磁场
They're all peaked, like we're plugged into some magnetic field.
-谁想知道原因？ -快说吧
-Well, who on this spaceship wants to know why?  [Sharp]-By all means.
本来要降落在第8区
The reason we were shooting for grid 8 is because...
因为第9区全是铁氧层
thermographics indicated that grid 9 was compressed iron ferrite.
你降落在铁板上了
Which means that you landed us on a goddamn iron plate.
你也听到了 把摇控卫星连线拿出来
All right. Well, you heard the man. Let's wheel out the remote satellite link.
希望还有一艘
We need that radio.  Oh, God, please tell me we still got one of 'em.
独立号没有反应
[Computers Beeping]  [Man] Independence has flatlined.
奥斯卡…
Oscar! Oscar!
天哪
Oh, God!
有人吗？
Hello! Anyone!
有人活着吗？救命呀
Is anyone else alive? Somebody, help me!
小杰
A.J.!
-你在哪里？ -我在这里
-Where are you?  -I'm here.
全都死了
Lev, there's no one else.
-没有人了 -我知道
-There's no one else.  -I know.
老天
[Bear] Oh, man.
-大熊，你在哪里？ -小杰…
[A.J.] Bear, where are you?  [Bear] A.J.? A.J.?
我在前面
[Bear] I'm in the shuttle, man.
-你没事吧？ -见到你真好
Are you all right?  I'm so glad to see you, man.
看到你这大丑哥真高兴
I never thought I'd be so happy to see your ugly face.
-休斯顿，收到吗？ 这是自由号 -检查推进器
Houston, do you read? This is Freedom.  [Sharp] Check your thrusters.
-休斯顿，收到吗？ -准备好了吗？
[Watts] Houston, do you copy?  [Sharp] Is everyone good to go?
到下面的峡谷去
[Harry] Down here! In the valley!
这是最可怕的噩梦
This place is like Dr. Seuss's worst nightmare.
用摇控卫星 接收的信号比较清楚
Let's get the remote satellite. We'll get better reception up there.
叫麦斯下来
[Harry] Bring Max down. Watch yourself through here, Max.
小心，麦斯
There're a couple big fissures.  To the left!
有很多裂缝 左边，开到左边
Bring it to the left!
色狼，过来勘查地质
[Harry] Rockhound, you come on down here and take some readings down in the flat spot.
氧化铁
[Beeping]  Iron ferrite.
-连线了 -我要回来，随时待命
-I have fire.  [Harry] Watts, I'm comin' back. Stand by.
-全都是铁，色狼 -我开始讨厌我什么都懂了
-Mostly iron, Rockhound.  -God, I hate knowing everything.
我保证铁层一定没有50英尺深
Well, I can pretty much guarantee it's not gonna be thicker than 50 feet.
-你怎么知道？ -要不然我们就完了
-How do you figure that?  -'Cause if it is, we're screwed.
-可以吗？ -挖洞吧
-Max, you good?  -Yeah. Just makin' hole.
-转过来 -臭外太空
-Turn it around.  [Max] Friggin' outer space.
看起来不错
It's good.
钻进去了，很顺利
All right. We're in. Another light. We're cuttin' through pretty good.
我没见过这些玩意
There's some stuff in here I ain't never seen.
钻深一点
All right, let's punch it down!  [Metal Creaking]
-你看到吗？ -我看到了，什么东西？
-Hey, Harry, did you see that?  -Yeah, Max, I see it. I see it. What is it?
-一个钻头坏了 -退出来
-We lost the bite in the bit.  -All right. Back it off. Back it off.
该死
Goddamn it!
钢柱扭曲，退出来 好，停住
Sounds like we twisted a shank. Back it out of there, Max. Good. Good. Hold 'er there.
这就像是希腊悲剧
Wow, this is a goddamn Greek tragedy.
-钻头又不是没断过 -只钻十英尺就断？
-We've all seen broken drill heads before.  -Not after ten feet.
-这种事我没见过 -现在见过了
-I never seen one.  -Well, now you've seen one.
-怎么办？ -把大钻头卸下来
-What do you want?  -Unpack the Judge.
大熊、勒夫
[A.J.] Bear, Lev.
我们只剩三个宇航员
[Lev] We're only three astronauts left now.
我们不是宇航员 只是油井钻工
[A.J.] We're not astronauts. We're oil drillers. We're not even supposed to be here.
什么？你们不是宇航员？
What? You're not astronaut?
我有办法了，上来吧
I'm getting us outta here. Get in.
-为什么？ -到穿山甲上，我有个主意
Why?  Just get in the Armadillo. I have an idea.
这里是自由号，收到吗？ 休斯顿，收到吗？
Houston, this is Freedom. Do you copy? Houston, do you copy? Freedom shuttle has
传送图像
[Radio Static Hissing]  We're gettin' some scattered video feeds here.
你收到吗？
[Watts] Houston, this is Freedom. Do you copy?
谢天谢地，自由号 这里是休斯顿
Thank God we have you, Freedom.  Freedom, this is Houston. Go ahead.
-别失去信号 -有信号了
-Don't lose 'em, Malloy.  -Sharp, I'm getting something.
-这里是自由号 我们安全降落 -在哪里？
Houston, this is Freedom. We have landed safely.  Where are they?
15H32
We are at site coordinates approximately 15H32
找出那个地区的资料，快点
Okay, I want to know everything we can about that location.  Got it.
电力和天线都有问题
Get it before we lose 'em.  We're also having electric and antenna difficulties.
-快找机械部 -我们已经开始钻洞
-Walter, get Mechanical on that.  -But we have commenced drilling.
快失去信号了，用四号天线
Stevens, we're losin' him. Bring it up on four. On four.  Come on.
还不知道能否返航
Shuttle flight capability not yet known.
加强信号
Bump the signal.  Bumping.  Houston. Houston.
失去信号，试着再连线,快把卫星天线架好
We lost 'em. Get 'em back. Gruber, we need that hookup.
我们都是这么硬来的
Show you how we do things where I come from.
坐好
Hold on!  [Metal Crumpling]
装好了
Seat it.
准备旋进去
All right, get ready. Max, thread it.
时间紧迫，快点
Guys, the clock is tickin'. Let's go, go, go, go, go!
转松
All right! Good! Crank it loose!
转速每秒2500 干活吧
Keep it at 25. Let's kick a little asteroid butt!
我要加强动力
All right, Chick. Give me more torque on the turbine, huh?
你要加强动力
[Drill Whining]  [Harry] Max, I need some more power down here!
好 换到四档
All right, boss.  Throw it in fourth, then drop the hammer.
钻穿这些臭屎吧
Let's drill through this turd.  [Harry] Come on, boys.
进度落后，动作要快 -快钻进去…把它钻穿吧
We gotta hop. We're fallin' behind. Dig, dig, dig. Chew this iron bitch up.
变速器卡住
Chick, the tranny's stuck.  Harry!
怎么了？
What is it?  Chick, come on! Help!
奇克，松开离合器
Release the clutch!  Pull it up!
这玩意动不了
Okay. Well, this thing's not movin'.
不行，快关掉
No, no, no! Shut it down! Shut it
没有用，哈瑞
This is not workin' out, Harry.
-你没事吧？ -变速器爆了
-Oh, are you all right?  -Oh, blew the tranny. Blew the tranny.
求求你，上帝
Come on, God.
我只想请你帮帮忙
Just a little help. That's all I'm askin'.
他可能听得到你
I think we're close enough. He might've heard ya.
坏消息 陨石经过月球前转动很稳定
Here's the bad news. Before the asteroid passed the moon,
35度的转轴
her rotation was stable at 32 degrees on an x axis.
现在你看看 月球引力把它推得乱转
But now look at this. The lunar gravity's put her in a spin.
-三个轴心都在转 -我们没想到
-She's tumbling on all three axes. -This wasn't expected, sir.
-这会影响通讯吗？ -会
What does this do for communications?  Not good.
只能再跟航天飞机连线七分钟
We'll have definite contact with the shuttle for only seven more minutes.
-然后就会失去联络 -几时能恢复正常？
-After that it's radio darkness.  -For how long?
七分钟后，可能就永远失去联络
And after seven minutes, we may never hear from them again.
我们试着
But we're trying to bounce a signal...
用俄国的军事卫星连线
off a Russian military satellite, reestablish contact that way.
如果失去联络,几时会丧失摇控引爆核弹的能力？
If we lose the shuttle com, when do we lose the ability to remote detonate that nuke?
核弹透过军事卫星引爆
The weapon remote receives a signal from a Milstar satellite.
轨道比较高，信号比较强
Higher orbit, more powerful transmitter.
和航天飞机连线七分钟后 还有五分钟能引爆核弹
If we've got the shuttle for seven minutes, we can remote detonate for an additional five.
也就是说十二分钟后
What he's trying to say, General, is that, uh, in 12 minutes' time,
就无法再引爆
you may lose the ability to detonate the nuke... permanently.
我得通知总统
I've got to inform the president.
我只想知道，被困在陨石上该怎么办
Just want to make sure you know we're stuck on an asteroid.
-你知道自己在做什么吗？ -不知道
Do you know what you're doing now?  No, no.
我不知道我在做什么
You know what? I have no idea what I'm doing. I have no idea.
也不知道这个按钮有什么用途
This button I don't know what that does, okay?
我只知道我们坠毁了
All I know is that we just crashed back there,
两个朋友死了，我们离哈瑞有25哩
I lost two of my friends, we're 25 miles from Harry's shuttle.
我不晓得他是不是活着
We don't know if he's alive. We don't know if he can fly. All I know is, there's a beep...
我现在只想找到这家伙
on this thing and I'm trying to get us there.
卸下变速器
Let's get it unpacked.
-怎么了？ -我从来没碰到过这种金属
-What's up?  -We're drilling through some kind of metal I've never seen before.
两个钻头坏掉 第一具变速器爆掉
It's fried two of our drill bits, and now we blew our first transmission.
-你们钻了多深？ -帮我把变速器抬下去
So how deep are we?  We could use your help with the transmission, Colonel.
我得进行评估报告 现在应该钻到两百英尺
I have an assessment report due now. We're supposed to be at 200 feet.
-现在钻了多深？ -你不要这么啰唆
So how deep are we?  Not as deep as we'll be...
快帮忙装变速器就会钻得更深
when you quit askin' me these questions and help us load this transmission on.
-现在的深度是多少？ -那并不重要，上校
-What is our current depth?  -Our current depth is not important, Colonel.
-重不重要由我决定 -我们得钻八百英尺
-I'll decide what's important. -We've got 800 feet to drill.
你钻了两个半小时 现在有多深？
You've had two and a half hours. Where are we?
57英尺
We're at 57 feet.
你有空的话 就帮我抬变速器
Now, if you're not too busy, maybe you can give us a hand with this transmission.
-夏普上校 -把它抬上去，我马上回来 -夏普上校
Colonel Sharp! Get this strapped up. I'll be right back. Colonel Sharp!
我们连上线了
All right. I'm coming through. We have contact. Over.
只能这样了
That's as clear as it's gonna get.
休斯顿，这是自由号 收到吗？
Houston, this is Freedom. Do you copy?
我正在使用摇控卫星连线
Working at a remote satellite link at this moment. Transmission change.
20分钟后换好变速器 十小时后才能钻好洞
Colonel!  Twenty minutes. Puts drilling final at ten hours.
到时候已经突破最后屏障 请指示
Please advise. That's four hours past the zero barrier. Please advise.
这算什么？ “进度表”
What the hell is this? "Zero depth"?
这是哪儿来的？ 你跟谁讲话？楚门吗？
And where'd this come from? Who are you talkin' to? Is that Truman?
-电话给我 楚门,钻洞就是这样
Lemme have that phone. Gimme the phone. Truman! Look, this is what happens when you drill.
不能依照空军的进度表进行
We cannot use your "U.S. Air Force Personnel Only" drill time card.
-这是谁写的？ -快失去信号了
Who wrote this thing, by the way?  We're losing coms again.
他听到吗？
Look Is he getting this? Does he hear me or What's wrong with this?
-通讯中断 -那是什么意思？
-The com's down.  -What do you mean, "the com's down"?
我们和指挥中心失去联络
[Sharp] What do I mean? I mean we've lost communication to mission control.
那就快把变速器换好
Fine. Let's go back to the cargo bay and get the transmission
你试过却失败了，明白吗？
Harry, guess what. You had your shot. You didn't do it. You understand me?
你尽管用这张进度表监督
You can't  Why don't you stay here [Shouting]
或是写报告什么的，随便你
Write a report, why don't ya? That'll be [Shouting Continues]
不过我们要把洞钻好
My men and I will go and get this hole dug!
你们是太空史上最大的错误
You and your men are the biggest mistake in the history of NASA.
失去联络
[Man] We've lost communication.  Oh, God.
-现在的情况不太妙 -这还用你说
-We're not lookin' too good right now.  -No shit.
我们得设法恢复通讯
We gotta get that radio back up.
总统先生，请你做决定
[Man] Mr. President, it's time to make a decision.
再过五分钟 就无法摇控引爆核弹
We can remote detonate the bomb for only another five minutes.
-我是金将军 -是的，总统先生
[Rings]  Yes? Kimsey here. -Yes, Mr. President.
我们也看到了
Yes, we saw that too, sir.
也许该等…
But maybe we should wait until they
丹，叫他们离开那里
Dan, get them out of there.
-马上撤退 -为什么？
Evac right now.  What's goin' on here?
我奉命接管这项任务
I've been ordered to override the system.
这算什么？
Well, what is this?
紧急程序
Secondary protocol.
他们还没有钻完
But they haven't drilled the damn hole yet!
总统的雇问认为钻洞来不及了
The president's advisors feel that the drilling isn't working.
很可能会失去无线电信号
And we've lost radio contact, maybe for good.
再过几分钟就不能摇控引爆核弹
We've only got a few minutes left of guaranteed ability to remote detonate that nuke.
再不引爆就会失去机会
If we don't do it now we could lose control, and we may never get it back.
叫总统开除他的雇问
Well, you tell the president that he better fire his socalled advisors.
在陨石表面引爆就会失去那枚核弹
If you detonate that nuke on the surface, we waste a perfectly good bomb,
和拯救地球的机会
and we have one chance to save this planet!
“紧急程序”
-把无线电修好,我要所有的电力 -知道了
-I need that radio. Gruber, give me everything you got now!  [Gruber] Roger that.
我知道，总统先生 不过我只想说
Yes, Mr. President, I understand that completely, but my point is very, very simple.
你要相信我，我了解状况
And I think you need to trust me on this because I know something about it.
我保证，你这么做会害死大家
I guarantee you, if you do this, you kill us all.
是的
Yes, sir.
将军，他找你
General, he wants you.
我是金将军
This is Kimsey. Yes, sir.
是的，我了解
I understand.
我奉命在三十秒后引爆核弹
The orders are to remote detonate in 30 seconds.
你还没告诉他们
You have not told them yet!
我爸在上面
That is my father up there!
你知道你不能这么做，你很清楚
This is one order you shouldn't follow, and you fucking know it!
放开她，放开她
Let her go. Let her go!
你的钥匙，长官
Your key, sir.
上帝保佑他们
[Consoles Beeping]  God be with them.
慢慢来
Slow it down.
“启动”
哈瑞
Harry...
那枚核弹的计时器在跳
the clock on that ninefoot nuclear weapon is ticking.
-我的天 -夏普，给我进来
-Oh, my God! -Sharp! Get back here now!
马上准备撤退
What? Get the shuttle ready to evac now!
-核弹突然启动，这是怎么回事？ -紧急程序
It just came on all by itself. What the hell's happening?  Secondary protocol.
-什么？ -紧急程序
What's that? What?  Secondary protocol.
-什么意思？ -紧急程序是什么？
What does that mean?  What the hell's secondary protocol?
他们要从地球引爆核弹
They're detonating this thing from Earth.  What do you mean, detonating?
引爆？我们都还没钻好洞
We haven't even drilled the hole yet!  We'll drop it in the hole.
快戴上头盔
What're you talkin' about?  The hole? Whoa, whoa!  Get your helmets on now!
不行，怎么关掉？我的手下在外面
Oh, no, no. HowHow you turn it off?  I got two men out on that rock!
我也有，我们得撤退
I got a man out there too. We gotta evac now.
色狼、麦斯 快回到航天飞机
Max, Rockhound, get back to the shuttle, doubletime!
他们也许正要下来
They could be on their way here.  They're not on their way here.
如果是的话，早就该看到他们了
They would've talked to us by now. We would've seen them.
封锁驾驶舱
Watts, air lock the cockpit now!  I copy you.
麦斯、色狼 等等，怎么把它关掉？
Max, Rockhound!  Hey, wait a minute! How do you turn this thing off?
哈瑞，收到吗？出事了
[Radio Static Hissing]  Harry, do you copy?  Somethin's wrong.
是啊，我们根本就不该来
Yeah, it's all wrong, man. We shouldn't even be up here.
回航天飞机吧
I know. Let's go back to the ship!
我不能丢下他们
I'm not leavin' without my men, Sharp.
两分钟内就得离开
We've got two and a half minutes to drop it and get off this rock.
他们赶不回来我们就走
If they're not back by the time we finish, we leave without 'em.
别这么复杂，把核弹关掉
Okay, let's simplify this. Let's just turn the bomb off right now.
要是不在八百英尺的地底下引爆核弹的话
If we don't put this bomb down in a hole 800 feet onto a fault line,
这只是一场昂贵的烟火秀
all you're gonna have is a real expensive fireworks show.
这好像一场噩梦
This is turnin' into a surrealistic nightmare here.
你听到吗？我是楚门
Watsler, are you listening? It's Truman.
听着，我要你切断信号,和卫星的通讯信号
Okay, listen to me carefully. I want you to kill it. Kill the uplink.
-给我时间钻洞，把核弹关掉 -这不是我的决定
-Give us the time, Sharp. Shut this bomb down now!  -It's not my call.
-是谁的决定？ -这命令一定是来自总统
-Then whose call is it?  -An order to detonate can only come from the president.
他不在这儿，快把核弹关掉
The president's not here! You've gotta give us more time!  Let's just turn it off now.
我不能决定
I'm telling you to shut this bomb down now!
你猜怎么着？
And I'm telling you it's not my call!  Well, guess what.
我就替你决定
I just made the call for you.  Harry!
住手，你会引爆它
Don't. You could set it off.
你带枪来太空干嘛？
Oh, man. What're you doin' with a gun in space?
快点，快关掉核弹 切断连线
Come on. Come on. We gotta stop that bomb right now. Kill the uplink.
-核弹会爆炸，快把它弄出航天飞机 -别乱来
-This thing is gonna blow. We gotta get it off the ship.  -Easy.
-别动 -关掉核弹，让我们继续
-Stand down, Sergeant.  -Shut this bomb down and let us finish our job the right way.
我得保护核弹
I'm under orders to protect a surface detonation.
我给你三秒钟 否则你就得向我开枪
I'm gonna give you three seconds to shut this bomb down, and then I'm gonna make you shoot me.
快点
Hurry, Watsler. For Christ's sake, hurry.
“切断”
[Detonator Powering Down]
怎么回事？
What happened?
长官，引爆指令被取消
Sir, the override It's been overridden.
只有几分钟，设法恢复信号，快点
I bought us a couple of minutes, so get that radio workin', okay? Hurry, hurry!
你大老远跑来 就是为了杀死我们吗？
Bring me all the way up here just to blow me and my friends up? Is that it?
听我说
[Gasping] Listen  Shut up!
闭嘴，上校，你别说话
Shut up, Colonel. I'm talking now.
核弹可能会再启动
[Sharp] It could start again. It might've been a warning.
所以你得拆除它
That's why you are gonna dismantle this bomb.
我们错过什么好戏？
All right. What'd we miss?
再试一次  去吧
Do it again.  Go.
继续试
Keep tryin'.
请你别反抗，马上走开 请你离开
Sir, I need you to cease and desist. I need your terminal... now.
-他们又启动核弹 -又启动了
-They're reactivating the bomb.  -Comin' back online, sir.
老天，又来了
[Detonator Blipping]  Oh, geez. Here we go again.
你来这儿有什么目的？
What're you doin' up here? And why did you even bother to make the trip?
奉命行事、完成任务
To do the right thing, to see that it's done.
想想你在做什么
For God's sakes, think about what you're doin'.
你为何要听十万哩外的命令
Why are you listenin' to someone that's 100,000 miles away?
在这儿没有人能帮我们
We're here. Nobody down there can help us.
如果我们失败人类就会灭亡
So if we don't get this job done, then everybody's gone.
只剩一分钟
One minute.
我钻了三十年的油井
I've been drillin' holes in the earth for 30 years.
每次都能钻到设定的深度
And I have never, never missed a depth that I have aimed for.
这次也能，我能钻到八百英尺
And by God, I am not gonna miss this one. I will make 800 feet.
-42秒 -不过我需要你的帮忙
Fortytwo seconds.  But I can't do it alone, Colonel. I need your help.
你要用你女儿的姓名发誓
You swear on your daughter's life, on my family's,
你钻得到那个深度
that you can hit that mark?
我钻得到八百英尺 我对天发誓
I will make 800 feet. I swear to God, I will.
那就拆除这枚弹头吧
Then let's turn this bomb off.
稳住，拆开来，线拉出来
Steady. Take it back. That's what you'll have to do. Get 'em off backwards.
-全部吗？ -全都要
Rainbow track? Under Under one? Under Okay.  All of 'em. All of 'em.
-没静电吧？ -好好干
-Okay. Are we free of static?  -Oh, do a good job. Do a good job.
稳住
Steady. Steady.  Good job. All right. All right.
-快，快 -红线A，剪断
Go! Go! Go! Red wire "A." Ready? And
快点…
Now. Come on! Come on! Come on! Come on!
负极B线
[Breathing Heavily]  Negative "B."
好好干…
Ready, and now.  Do a good job. Do a good job.  Track flipped. Hots in.
红还是蓝？
It better be. Go.  Red or blue?  [Beeping Faster]
红
Re
蓝
Blue.
干得好
Good job!
这里真讨厌
Oh, God, it sucks up here.
-计时器停在三秒 -什么？
Sir, the clock has stopped at three seconds.  What?
完全失去联络了？
Have we lost complete radio contact?
我成功了，俄国卫星接收到微弱信号
I got some magic happening. We're bouncing off Russian and French satellites.
休斯顿，收到吗？
It may have a faint signal.  Houston? Houston, do you copy?
请说，自由号
Go ahead, Freedom.
休斯顿，你有个问题
Houston, you have a problem Problem.
我答应女儿我要回家
See, I promised my little girl that I'd be comin' home.
不管你们怎么想，我们都得钻洞
Now, I don't know what you people are doin' down there, but we got a hole to dig up there.
好啊,我们接着干活
[Cheering]  Go, go, go, go! Come on. We got work to do.
很好，绝不放弃，怎么样？
Okay, guys. All go, no quit. How ya doin' down there? Good?
装好变速器，干活吧
Okay, got the tranny. We're back in business.
你们应该休息一下，过来看看
Hey, you guys should take a break and come up and see this.
地球好美，
Wow. Got a great view of the Earth from here.
可惜回不去了
Too bad we'll never set foot on her again.
-勒夫，看到什么了吗？ -没有
-Lev, do you see anything?  -No.
继续前进，我不会放弃
Well, keep goin'. I'm not givin' up.
停下来，大熊
Hold up here, Bear.
老天
[Lev] Oh, boy.  [A.J.] This is great.
太好了，在陨石上碰到大峡谷
We just happen to run into the Grand Canyon on the asteroid?
我就说你走错路了
I told you, you took a wrong way, a wrong road.
什么？这地方哪儿来的路？
[A.J.] WhatWhat road? Do you see any roads around here?
我不想扫你的兴
[Lev] You know what? I do not have much pleasure being near God's ear.
不过这样好吗？
But you think this is looking good, or what?
勒夫，拜托你给我住嘴
Lev, why don't you just do humanity a favour and just shut the hell up?
你看过飞车特技吗？
Have you ever heard of Evel Knievel?
我没看过“星球大战”
No, I never saw Star Wars.
很好，你们干得很好
All right. Doin' a good job.
-深度多少？ -150英尺
-Give me a depth reading, Max.  -We're 150 feet, Harry.
骑吧，牛仔
Ride 'em, cowboy! Yippeekaiyo, kaiyay!
从核弹上面下来
Get off... the nuclear... warhead.
我在学“奇爱博士”里面
I was doin' that guy from that movie, you know,
骑着核弹的那场戏
Slim Pickens, where he rides it all the way in the nuclear warhead.
-下来 -你没看过吗？
-Now.  -Oh, you didn't see that one, huh?
还得钻700英尺，色狼
We got 700 feet of hole to dig, Rockhound.
我只是想感受胯下的威力
All right. JustJust wanted to feel the power between my legs, brother.
夏普
Hey, Sharp.
反对核武！反对核武！
[Chanting] No nukes! No nukes! No nukes!
你的枪还有子弹吗？
You got any more bullets in that gun, Sharp?
华特说被踢一脚就会漂出去
[A.J.] What did Watts tell you, Bear? If she kicked you in the balls, you'd keep floating.
关掉推进器，
[A.J.] We turn the thrusters off,
让它漂过去
we jump this thing, we float right over it.
再说一遍
Go over it again, Lev.
我们一离地，就关掉推进器
Throw the jet thrusters off exactly when we jump.  Okay.
只要再启动就能降落
And then we're gonna put them on, and we gonna go down nice and slow.
没错，没错 能成功吗？
That's it. That's it, baby. That's it.  Is this gonna work?
-不知道 -说说谎话安慰我嘛
-I don't know.  -Lev, you know what, just lie to me.
也许有五成把握
Let's say 5050 No. More like, uh
不，七、八成吧
like 7030 or 8020.
成功了你们就是英雄,跟我一样
But you know what? If it works, the two of you gonna be heroes, just like me.
管它的，跳过去吧
Screw it. We're jumpin' over this canyon.
老实说，这点子很烂
Just for the record, this is a very bad idea!
到了悬崖再关掉
Wait for the edge. Don't hit it till we get there.  I'm waiting.
来了
[Lev] Three.  [A.J. Chattering]
二…一，关掉！
[Lev] Two. One!
成功了！
Yes! It's working!  It's working!
我是天才 等一下
I'm a genius! Wait a minute.  Whoa. Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa!
-前面有岩石 -左转，左转
We got some rocks!  Go left! Go left!
没办法
Lev, Lev, I can't do anything!
我们要漂到外太空了
Oh, okay, okay, we're floating into outer space.
这是个问题
Check main switch.  Uh, this could be a little bit of a problem.
-启动推进器 -启动
Thrusters on... now!  All right, turn 'em on.
怎么了？
[Rattling]  What's wrong?
不晓得，推进器失效 这个臭机器
II don't know. TheThe thrusters not working. I hate this machine!
你不是计划好了？
I thought you had this planned! What're we supposed to do?  Be quiet! I must think!
-让我想想，我要出去 -你要出去？
I'm stepping outside.  You'reYou're going outside?
只有我是合格的宇航员 我要救你们这些美国佬
I am the only certified astronaut, and I'm saving your American ass!
谁叫你要听他的
Yes. You'll listen to him. Right.
快点，离地面已经有一哩了
Hurry up, Lev, because we're about a mile off the asteroid!
等等，燃料管结冰了
Just a second. The fuel line is iced up.
-应该可以了 -还是不行
I think maybe workin' now.  No, Lev, it's not working!
抱歉，我算错机率了
I'm sorry, A.J. I was way off the odds.
越来越高了
[Bear] We're gettin' higher, man.  Look out!
小心，有岩石！
The rocks! Rocks are coming!
抓紧了
Hold on!  Aah!
-启动推进器 -勒夫，小心
Pull the thrusters!  Lev, look out!
-勒夫不见了 -小杰
We lost Lev.  A.J.! [Grunting]
小杰，推进器
A.J., the thrusters!  Aah!
推进器启动了
Let's get Lev back!
抓紧，要降落了
Lev, hold on! We're comin' in!
谢天谢地，阿弥陀佛，谢谢…
Thank You, Jesus. Thank You, Lord. Thank You. Thank You, thank You, thank You, thank You.
-我是真正的俄国大英雄 -我就说吧
-Now I'm really a Russian hero!  -I told you!
一定能成功
I know!  I knew this would work!
我算得没错
Good odds, you know?  Come on, Lev.
上来，快走吧
Get in here. We gotta go.  Yah!
你要注意变速器
Rockhound, keep on that transmission.
没问题
Tranny looks good, Harry.  All right. Take it outta there.
好，放下去吧 锁住了
Lock it down, Chick.
太棒了
Nice.
怎么没玩过这个？
How come we didn't get any training on this thing?
酷毙了，我一个人就能搞定这陨石
Whoa. Very cool. I could take out this asteroid singlehandedly.
让我接手吧
[Machine Whirring]  Okay, boys, give it a rest. I'll take it from here.
搞什么？
What the hell is that?  It's Rockhound.  Whoa.
真好玩，太爽了
This is so much fun, it's freaky.
色狼
Rockhound!  [Cheering]
小心头，抱歉，哈瑞
Whoa, watch your heads. Sorry, Harry.
快让开
Outta my way, boys!  Rockhound!
臭陨石，去死吧
Meet your maker, asteroid!  [Both Grunting]
-你是怎么了？ -太疯狂了
-What the hell's the matter with you, Rockhound? Goddamn!  -This is insane.
-你疯了吗？ -他有太空妄想症
-Have you lost your mind?  -No.  He's got space dementia.
看好你的手下
Harry, you want to watch your man.
麦斯,换到倒档，把管子弄出来
Max, downshift and put it in reverse. We gotta get that pipe outta there.
怎么回事？ -地面裂开来,地震
-What's happening?  -The ground's cracking!  -Earthquake!
快关掉
Quick, shut it off!
快关掉…天然气爆发
Shut it off! Shut it off now!  We're gonna have a blowout!
挖到天然气层,压力太大了
We hit a gas pocket!  We got pressure out the ass!
麦斯，快戴头盔，要爆发了
Max, get your helmet on! Max, she's gonna blow!
-老天，好烫 -快走吧
Aah! Oh, Jesus, I'm cooking!  Max, get outta there!
完了,哈瑞！
This is it! Harry!
我快被烫死了
I'm bailing!
麦斯
Max!
永别了，麦斯
Goodbye, Max.
安息吧，伙计
Max!  Take care, buddy.
穿山甲不见了,天然气爆发
Armadillo's off the scope.  I think we've had a blowout.  No sign of the Armadillo.
通知楚门
Get ahold of Truman.
让世界知道噩耗
Prepare the world for bad news.
根据未经证实的消息
[Male Newscaster #1] We're getting sketchy information that the mission...
太空任务遭遇重大挫折
has suffered massive failure.
我们正在
And what we're trying to do right now...
打听确切的消息
is to confirm that and find out exactly what that means.
据赶回家和家人团聚的
Repeat: We're getting leaks from several NASA officials,
太空总署官员透露
some rushing home to be with their families,
钻洞行动不成功
that the drilling was unsuccessful.
这是人类灭亡的前夕
[Male Newscaster #2] This could very well be our final hour.
我们要结束转播
[Male Newscaster #4] We're gonna go off the air now.
祝好运，上帝保佑大家
Good luck and God bless.
有陨石掉落
[Man #1] We've got incoming.  [Man #2] I got tracks.
欧洲一共有四颗，
NORAD's tracking four small incoming over Europe.
一颗就快要击中巴黎
I think one's about to hit near Paris.
根据报导…
[All Shouting]  Reports are coming in.
42国实施戒严令
[Male Newscaster #1] Martial law has been implemented in 42 countries.
当陨石突破最后屏障
[Male Newscaster #2] Once the asteroid hits zero barrier,
3小时57分后将撞上地球
it will take about three hours and 57 minutes to impact Earth.
我们得奉总统命令叫他们撤离
I guess we do it the president's way.
然后摇控引爆核弹
I'll order an evac. You can remote detonate.
-你还是认为无效？ -已经无所谓了
You still don't think this'll work, do you?  What I think is irrelevant.
-我们必须马上引爆 -好吧
[Kimsey] We need to do it now.  -Fine.
-他们能起飞吗？ -希望能
-Can they still take off?  -We hope so.
都是你害的
You are the one that pulled them into this!
他们是我的家人,别说你希望能
That is my family up there, so I don't wanna hear, "We hope so"!
猜怎么着？面对死亡吧
Guess what, guys? It's time to embrace the horror.
我们能亲眼目睹地球灭亡
Look. We got frontrow tickets to the end of the Earth.
耶 干得好
Yeah!  Way to go, baby!  Harry!
哈瑞，怎么样？
Yo, Harry! What's up, baby?
把核弹抬走，钻洞吧
Hey, get that bomb outta there! We got a hole to make!
休斯顿，难以置信，
[Sharp] Houston, you're not gonna believe this,
另一架穿山甲到了
but the other Armadillo has arrived.
大伙听着，冷静下来
[Cheering, Applauding]  All right, people, listen up. Settle down and focus.
你男朋友回来了
Mechanical, get online.  P.P.O., gimme a setup.  Your boyfriend's back.
哈瑞，来吧
[Bear] Yo, Harry!  [Shouting]
哈瑞，想我吗？
Hey, Harry. You miss me?
小杰，我只想说五个字
A.J., I got just five words for ya.
-能见到你真好 -那是六个字
-Damn glad to see ya, boy!  -That's six words.
-带他们去吧 -洞在哪里？
Chick, walk 'em down.  [A.J.] So where's this hole you need dug?
重新开始钻洞
[Watts] Houston, drilling has recommenced.
一小时内能钻250英尺吗？
Do you think they can drill 250 feet in an hour?
最好能
They better.
固定好
Bring that piece on in, Bear.
最高动力
Tractor pull.
钻臂降下 还有250英尺
I'm comin' down!  We got 250 feet to go.
这是 最后一具变速器和钻头
It's our last transmission, last drill head.
一档，钻吧，下去了
Punch it through. First gear. We got contact.
-钻进去吧，小杰 -我来了，钻吧
Come on down, A.J.  [Grunting] I got this, man. Let's go!
检查右引擎 飞行前检查没反应
Lev, the right engine hub. Houston, I'm getting no response from the preflight sequence.
不公平，拜托帮我松绑
[Muffled] Come on, now. This is not Hey Hey, come here.
勒夫，右引擎
[Watts] Lev, the right engine  Okay.
我只是想在临死前及时行乐
Lemme outta here, will ya? Just tryin' to have some fun before I die!
-有多深？ -770英尺
-How deep are we?  -Seven seventy.
-又有问题 -又有活动
-Whoa, they got problems.  -The gauges are spiking.
关掉，退出来
Methane! Shut it down! Back it down!
不能退，没时间了
I can't pull back now. The bit'll get lodged. We don't have enough time!
会爆掉的,麦斯就是这样死的
Whoa, whoa, whoa! It's gonna blow! It's how we lost Max!
相信我，钻得过去的，没问题
I know what I'm talkin' about. We can punch through this. We can knock this outta the park.
只剩这架变速器
This is our last transmission, A.J.
该死，若是只能相信我一次
Goddamn it, if you're ever gonna trust me, ever,
那就是现在了
once in your life, trust me now!
-会爆的 -我能办到，你要相信我
-Harry, it's gonna blow!  -Harry, I know what I'm doin'. You just gotta trust me.
由你决定
Make the call.
我要继续钻
All right. Hold on. I'm pushin' through her.
钻过去了
I'm pushin' through her!
-深度多少？ -775英尺、780英尺
-What's your depth?  -Seven seventyfive. Seven eighty.
钻到姥姥家吧
Take it up, baby! Ram it home!
钻下去，小杰
[Grunts] Drive on down, A.J.!
785英尺，加油
Seven eightyfive. Come on. Come on.
加油，小杰
Come on, A.J.!  Punch it!  Ninetyone. Come on.
792英尺、795英尺
Seven ninetytwo. Seven ninetyfive!
钻呀
Drive it down, A.J.!
797英尺、799英尺
Seven ninetyseven! Ninetynine!
钻过去了,802英尺，成功了
Breakthrough!  Eight hundred! Eightohtwo, Harry!
成功了
Yeah!  We did it!
[All Cheering]  Yes!  We did it!
干得好
Yeah! Kid, way to go!  I knew it, baby!
他们得把核弹放进洞里,只剩下38分钟
It's not over till we get the bomb down that hole.  Watts, they've got 38 minutes.
哈瑞，你得让开
[Sharp] Harry, you've gotta give me that hole.
等我两分钟，管子卡住了
I'm gonna need two more minutes. I got a bent pipe jammed in the hole.
我们得把它取出来
We gotta cut it out before we can send that bomb down. A.J.!
-小杰，准备好了？ -准备好了
She good to go?  Yeah, I'm all set.
好
All right.
你要快点
All right.  [Harry] A.J., come on! Make it fast!
我会尽快，下面的气压很高
I'm goin' as fast as I can! There's a lot of gas pressure!
感觉到吗？
You feel that?
哈瑞，快点，核弹准备好了
Harry, you gotta give me that hole. The bomb is almost ready.
快好了，
[Harry] Pull that pipe out!  Harry, I'm almost through!
再给我15秒
Give me 15 more seconds!  [Rumbling]
这倒是没见过
Well, this is somethin' new.
这颗陨石讨厌我们
[Crashing]  I don't think this thing likes us.
因为我们要毁了它
That's 'cause it knows we're here to kill it.  Whoa!
上面怎么了？
Hey, what's goin' on up there?
-小杰 -搞什么？
A.J.!  What the hell was that?
我好了
A.J.!  Goddamn it, I'm finished!
-你没事吧？ -气压很高
-A.J., you all right?  -Oh, lot of gas pressure in here, man!
-拉我上去 -是氢气
-Get me out!  -Whoa, whoa, whoa! Hydrogen pocket!
救命啊！
Oh! Harry! Pull me in!
小杰，撑着点
[Grunting]  Aah! A.J., hang on!
保护核弹
Secure the bomb!
夏普，小心
Sharp, heads up!
古柏，快跑
Gruber! Get outta there now!
快跑
[Whimpering] Oh, God, no!
你相信吗？
Do you believe that just happened?  [Gas Hissing]
-夏普，你没事吧？ -我没事
-Sharp, you all right?  -I'm okay.
-大熊？ -没事，我在这儿
-Bear?  -Yeah. I'm here, Harry.
-小杰 -我没事
-A.J.?  -Yeah, I'm okay.
我们失去古柏
[Gas Hissing]  We lost Gruber.
古柏死了
Gruber's dead.
把核弹装好回家吧
Let's get that bomb ready and go home.
糟糕了 “错误”
[Sharp] Oh, my God.  [Beeping]
-有问题吗？ -计时器和摇控器坏了
Is there a problem, Colonel?  The timer, the remote, the whole thing's dead.
核弹坏了？
What, the bomb is dead?
遥控引爆器一定是刚才被石块打坏了
No, the trigger's dead. It must've gotten damaged during the rock storm.
那该怎么引爆？
So how do we detonate it?
-再过18分钟就突破最后屏障 -有坏消息
We have 18 minutes to zero barrier. We got some bad news.
摇控引爆器受到损坏
The remote detonator on the bomb has been damaged.
有人得留下来引爆
That means that somebody's gonna have to stay behind.
航天飞机要两个人驾驶
It takes two people to fly this thing.
不想留下来等死的话 你们就得抽签决定
Either we all stay and die, or you guys draw straws.
我说咱们留下来等死,这是我的想法
I say we all stay and die. But that's me.
我愿意抽签，抽签吧
I'll draw. Let's draw.
不必抽签
Nobody's gonna draw straws.
-我留下来引爆 -不行
I'll stay and take care of it.  Well, I can't live with that sort of thing.
没人问你
Nobody asked you if you could live with it, all right?  Bullshit!
我不能让你自愿牺牲
No way I will let you volunteer for this...
然后良心不安地回家
so I can go back to my home country like the man who didn't volunteer.
不行
No way!
咱们抽签决定谁留下来
Hey, man, let's draw, and let's see who's gonna stay up here and dance.
你们一定觉得我疯了
Guys, lll know you guys think I'm crazy right now,
不过我想留下来
but I would really like this responsibility.
好吧
All right. All right.
-我能搞定 -那就抽吧
I can do it.  Let's just draw straws and get it over with. Come on.
我才不跟你抽签
I ain't drawin' against you, Harry.
我要跟你抽签，快抽吧
Well, I'm gonna draw against you, Chick, so you better just go ahead and do it.
给我吧
Just gimme this thing.
这算好还是不好？
Is this good or bad?
老天
Oh, man.
人难逃一死，对吧？
Well, we all gotta die, right?
至少我能拯救世界
I'm the guy who gets to do it saving the world.
快点，只剩十分钟
So, uh, let's go. WeWe got about ten minutes, right?
把这个插进插座
You plug this into the port.
拉起来然后按住 就这样
Lift, press, hold. That's it.
拉起来按住，应该不难,连我都不会搞砸
Lift, press, hold. Shouldn't be too tough. Even I can't screw this up.
我带他下去
I'll take him down.
帮我个忙
Do me a favour, will ya?
告诉葛瑞丝
Just tell Grace that, uh
我会永远和她在一起，好吗？
that I'll always be with her, okay?
好不好？
Can you do that?
好吧，小子
Yeah. Okay, kid.
把这交给楚门
Give this to Truman.
一定要给他,进去吧
Make sure Truman gets that. Get in there.
轮到我表现了
It's my turn now.
哈瑞
[Gasping] Harry! Harry!
你不能这样,这是我的使命
You can't do this to me! It's my job!
你要照雇我女儿 那才是你的使命
You go take care of my little girl now. That's your job.
其实我一直都把你当儿子
Always thought of you as a son.
一直都是
Always.
你和葛瑞丝结婚我会很高兴
But I'd be damn proud to have you marry Grace.
你要保重
Harry.  You take care of yourself.
我爱你，孩子
Harry, no!  I love you, pal.
我也爱你，等等，哈瑞
Harry, I love you! Don't, Harry! Wait a minute!
永别了
My son.  Don't do this, Harry!
别这样，哈瑞…
Don't do this! Harry!
怎么回事？
What happened?
那个固执的疯子
That crazy, stubborn son of a
这真是个好点子
Well, this was a real good idea.
快点，夏普 快把他们带走
All right, let's go, Sharp. Let's get our team outta here.
准备启动推进器
Come on! Let's get ready to initiate thrusters! Let's go!
坐好了
Strap it in, guys!  Get the O2 masks.
检查燃料，可以了吗？
Are they green? Are they green?
我不敢相信… 你没事吧？
I can't believe this is going down like this. You all right?
关闭通风孔、输入燃料 引擎没有问题
O2 vents locked, pressure loaded.  Engine board is green.
休斯顿，收到吗？ 我是哈瑞·史坦普
Houston, do you copy? This is Harry Stamper.
我们要在三分钟后离开
[Man] Houston, we're outta here in T minus three minutes.
爸爸？
Daddy! [Chuckling]
葛瑞丝
Hi, Gracie. Hi, honey.
乖女儿,我知道我答应你要回去
Grace, I know I promised you I was comin' home.
我不明白
I don't under understand.
看来我得食言了
[Sighs] Looks like I'm gonna have to break that promise.
我也骗了你
I, um I lied to you, too,
我说我跟你不同
when I told you that I didn't want to be like you.
其实我跟你一样
Because I am like you.
如果我有什么优点 这都是来自你
And everything good that I have inside of me, I have from you.
我好爱你
I love you so much, Daddy.
我以你为荣
I'm so proud of you.
我好怕
I'm so scared.
我好害怕
我知道，很快你就不必害怕了
I know it, baby, but there won't be anything to be scared of soon.
我要你知道，小杰救了我们,是真的
Gracie, I want you to know that A.J. saved us. He did.
跟奇克说...
I want you to tell Chick...
没有他我就办不到
that I couldn't have done it without him, none of it.
好好照雇小杰
I want you to take care of A.J.
我真希望能陪你走上红地毯
I wish I could be there to walk you down the aisle.
不过…
But I'll
我会时常去看你的
[Sighs] I'll look in on you from time to time, okay, honey?
我爱你，葛瑞丝
I love you, Grace.
我也爱你
[Crying] I love you too.
-我得走了 -爸爸，别走
-I gotta go now, honey.  -Daddy, no.
爸爸，不…
No, no, Dad, no.
启动导航系统，输入燃料
[Watts] O.M.S. pod prestart. O2 vents locked, pressure loaded.
怎么回事？你们怎么还不走？
What the hell's goin' on up there? Why haven't you guys left yet?
我们要走了，休斯顿
We're going, Harry. Houston.
-启动导航系统 -确认
We got O.M.S. pod prestart.  Pod prestart confirmed.
怎么了？不知道
What's the problem?  I don't know.
快去修好
What's wrong?  Fix it now!
来不及了
No time, no time!
怎么回事？
What?  What's that?
你上哪儿？
Where you goin'?  Come on. We're stayin', we're goin'.
到底要不要走嘛？赶快决定吧
We're stayin', we're goin'. Make up your minds.
快走吧，不到三分钟了
Sharp, get out of here now. You got less than three minutes.
快呀，华特
Come on, Watts. Come on, come on.
引爆吧，我们与你同在
Blow the bomb, Harry. We're with you.
-卡住了 -退后，你不懂这些设备
-Uh, it's stuck. -Yes?  You don't know the components!
美国设备、俄国设备,全都是台湾制造
Components, American components, Russian components. All made in Taiwan!
时间不多了
We're gettin' tight for ignition, Freedom.
休斯顿，引擎点不着
Houston, we've got no fire.
-什么意思？ -航天飞机坏了
-What does that mean?  -It means we got a busted ship.
航天飞机坏了？我却被绑在这儿
A busted ship? And I'm strapped in here.
我本来在外面有好座位的
I had a great spot picked out there.
快启动引擎，来不及了
Freedom, you fire that engine. If there's not a way, you find a way. The clock's tickin'.
快启动引擎
Let's go! Let's fire that engine, Freedom!
只剩一分钟 别以为我不会引爆
You got less than a minute. Don't think I won't blow this thing.
快走，情况不妙
Sharp, get out of here. It's gettin' bad down here.
让我来修理
I know how to fix it. Please, move.
你不滚开我就不客气
II have to take you away if you don't move.
快启动引擎
Watts, you gotta get that shuttle started. You gotta fire it up now!
夏普，快起飞
Damn it, Sharp. Get off this rock!
我叫你让开
I'm telling you, please, move! This is how we fix problem...
我都是这么修理俄国空间站的
in the Russian space station.
我不想再留在这里了
Because I don't want to stay here any more.
终于能回家了
[Whirring]  Yeah! Finally! We can go home!
终于好了…可以了
She's coming back. She's coming back.  We're hot!
快点，快点
Watts! Let's go, let's go!
尽管闹吧，臭石头
Rain all you want, you son of a bitch.
快，来不及了
Let's go! We don't have time! Hurry, hurry. We got no time!
准备启动推进器，
Initiate thrusters on my mark!
二、一…
Two, one, mark!
快升空，快点…
Come on. Get some altitude. Let's go, let's go.
最大动力
Freedom has max thrust!
谢谢你，哈瑞
Thank you, Harry.
航天飞机飞远了 还没有引爆核弹
Shuttle's out of range. Still no detonation.
事情不对劲
Something's not right. Too much time has gone by.
一分钟后突破最后屏障
Zero barrier's about to be breached. One minute.
快按下按钮
Harry, come on. Press that button.
-我们回去引爆 -不，再等一分钟
We're goin' back and do it ourselves.  Just don't. Wait one minute.
-就快突破最后屏障 -哈瑞，快按钮
Dan, we're about to cross the threshold.  Come on. Press the button.
上校，请你再等一分钟
Colonel, I'm askin' you. Just one more minute!
快按呀
Press the button, Stamper.
哈瑞一定办得到的
Harry'll do it. I know it.
他绝不会失败
He doesn't know how to fail.
我们赢了，葛瑞丝
We win, Gracie!
快按吧
Press it!  [Beeping]
引爆成功，引爆成功
[Man On P.A.] We have detonation. Confirming detonation.
陨石错过地球约四百哩
The two halves are gonna miss us by 400 miles...
碎片大部分都被气化
and most of the small particles have been vaporized.
-休斯顿，我们回来了 -收到，自由号
-Houston, we're comin' home.  -We copy that, Freedom.
哈瑞，你是最棒的
Yo, Harry, you the man.
肯尼迪中心，我看到跑道了,真是太美了
Kennedy, we see you. And you never looked so good.
我没提过，我最恨飞行
I never told anybody this before but I hate flyin',
所以现在摔死就太冤枉
so it'd be an awful shame to die now.
你这还不算惨,我跟高利贷借了十万块
That's easy for you to say. I owe 100 grand to a badass loan shark...
全都花在脱衣舞娘身上
which I spent on a stripper named Molly Mounds.
是吗？真糟糕
Boy, that's bad.
肯尼迪中心，副翼完全放下
Kennedy, we are 100 percent. Flap suspension control on full.
欢迎回家，宇航员
[Man] Welcome home, astronauts.
现在我们是大英雄
Hey, guys, remember: We're heroes now.
兄弟们，别把我在上面
So that incident with me and the gun on the asteroid,
发疯的事说出来，好吗？
let's keep that under wraps, all right?
史坦普小姐
Miss Stamper.
我是美国空军上校夏普
Colonel Willie Sharp, United States Air Force, ma'am.
令尊是我见过最勇敢的人
Requesting permission to shake the hand of the daughter...
请允许我和你握手
of the bravest man I've ever met.
我的天,我的英雄
Oh, my God!  Hi, you're my hero.
宝贝，我想跟你生个孩子
Oh, baby, I wanna have babies with you.
欢迎回来，牛仔
Welcome back, cowboy.
哈瑞要你收下这个
Uh, Harry wanted you to have this.
是么…
He did, huh?
* I could stay awake *
* Just to hear you breathin' *
* Watch you smile while you are sleepin' *
* While you're far away and dreamin' *
* I just wanna stay with you *
* In this moment forever *
* Forever and ever *
* I don't wanna close my eyes *
* I don't wanna fall asleep *
* 'Cause I miss you, baby *
* And I don't wanna miss a thing *
* 'Cause even when I dream of you *
* The sweetest dream would never do *
* I'd still miss you, baby *
* And I don't wanna miss a thing *
* And I don't wanna miss one smile *
* And I don't wanna miss one kiss *
* Well, I just wanna be with you right here *
* With you just like this *
* Well, I just wanna hold you close *
* Feel your heart so close to mine *
* And just stay here in this moment *
* For all the rest of time *
* Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah *
* Yeah *
* Don't wanna close my eyes *
* I don't wanna fall asleep *
* 'Cause I miss you, baby *
* And I don't wanna miss a thing *
* 'Cause even when I dream of you *
* The sweetest dream would never do *
* I'd still miss you, baby *
* And I don't wanna miss a thing *
* Don't wanna close my eyes *
* I don't wanna fall asleep *
* Yeah I don't wanna miss a thing **
** [Woman Vocalizing]
* All my bags are packed I'm ready to go *
* I'm standin' here outside your door *
* I hate to wake you up to say goodbye *
* But the dawn is breakin' It's early morn *
* The taxi's waitin' He's blowin' his horn *
* Already I'm ready I'm so lonesome *
* I could die *
* So kiss me and smile for me *
* Tell me that you'll wait for me *
* Hold me like you'll never let me go *
* 'Cause I'm leaving on a jet plane *
* I don't know when I'll be back again *
* Oh, babe I hate to go *
* I'm leaving on a jet plane *